<?xml version="1.0" encoding="US-ASCII"?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//Atypon//DTD Archiving and Interchange DTD Suite with ACHS extensions v2.2 20080601//EN" "archivearticle.dtd">
<article article-type="rapid-communication" dtd-version="2.2" xml:lang="EN"  xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML">
<front><journal-meta>
<journal-id journal-id-type="publisher">nalefd</journal-id><journal-title>Nano Letters</journal-title><abbrev-journal-title abbrev-type="publisher">Nano Lett.</abbrev-journal-title><issn pub-type="ppub">1530-6984</issn><issn pub-type="epub">1530-6992</issn><publisher><publisher-name>American Chemical Society</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/nl104209c</article-id><article-categories>
<subj-group subj-group-type="type-of-article">
<subject>Letter</subject>
</subj-group>
</article-categories>
<title-group>
<article-title>In-situ X-ray Absorption Study of Evolution of Oxidation States and Structure of Cobalt in Co and CoPt Bimetallic Nanoparticles (4 nm) under Reducing (H<sub>2</sub>) and Oxidizing (O<sub>2</sub>) Environments</article-title>
</title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author" id="ath1"><name><given-names>Fan</given-names><x> </x><surname>Zheng</surname></name><xref rid="aff1">&#x2020;</xref><xref rid="notes-1"/><x>, </x></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" id="ath2"><name><given-names>Selim</given-names><x> </x><surname>Alayoglu</surname></name><xref rid="aff1">&#x2021;</xref><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff2">&#xa7;</xref><xref rid="notes-1"/><x>, </x></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" id="ath3"><name><given-names>Jinghua</given-names><x> </x><surname>Guo</surname></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff3">&#x2225;</xref><x>, </x></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" id="ath4"><name><given-names>Vladimir</given-names><x> </x><surname>Pushkarev</surname></name><xref rid="aff1">&#x2021;</xref><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff2">&#xa7;</xref><x>, </x></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" id="ath5"><name><given-names>Yimin</given-names><x> </x><surname>Li</surname></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff2">&#xa7;</xref><x>, </x></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" id="ath6"><name><given-names>Per-Anders</given-names><x> </x><surname>Glans</surname></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff3">&#x2225;</xref><x>, </x></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" id="ath7"><name><given-names>Jeng-lung</given-names><x> </x><surname>Chen</surname></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff3">&#x2225;</xref><xref rid="afn2"/><x>, and </x></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes" id="ath8"><name><given-names>Gabor</given-names><x> </x><surname>Somorjai</surname></name><xref ref-type="corresp" rid="cor1">*</xref><xref rid="aff1">&#x2020;</xref><xref ref-type="aff" rid="aff2">&#xa7;</xref><x> </x></contrib><aff id="aff1"><sup>&#x2020;</sup>Materials Sciences Division and <sup>&#x2021;</sup>Chemical Sciences Division, <institution>Lawrence Berkeley National Lab</institution>, Berkeley, CA</aff><aff id="aff2"><label>&#xa7;</label>Department of Chemistry, <institution>University of California Berkeley</institution>, Berkeley, CA</aff><aff id="aff3"><label>&#x2225;</label>Advanced Light Source, <institution>Lawrence Berkeley National Lab</institution>, Berkeley, CA</aff></contrib-group><author-notes><corresp id="cor1"><label>*</label>E-mail: <email xlink:href="somorjai@berkeley.edu">somorjai@berkeley.edu</email>.</corresp></author-notes><pub-date pub-type="ppub"><day>09</day><month>02</month><year>2011</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>19</day><month>01</month><year>2011</year></pub-date><volume>11</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>847</fpage><lpage>853</lpage><supplementary-material xlink:href="nl104209c_si_001.pdf" id="sifile1"/>
<history><date date-type="received"><day>02</day><month>12</month><year>2010</year></date><date date-type="rev-recd"><day>06</day><month>01</month><year>2011</year></date><date date-type="asap"><day>19</day><month>01</month><year>2011</year></date><date date-type="issue-pub"><day>09</day><month>02</month><year>2011</year></date></history><permissions><copyright-statement>&copy; 2011 American Chemical Society</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2011</copyright-year><copyright-holder>American Chemical Society</copyright-holder></permissions><related-article related-article-type="pdf" xlink:href="nl104209c.pdf"/>
<abstract><p>In-situ near edge X-ray absorption fine structure spectroscopy was performed to monitor the oxidation states of Co and CoPt nanoparticles (NPs) of 4 nm size in the presence of H<sub>2</sub> and O<sub>2</sub> in the pressure range of 1 bar and 36 Torr respectively. Platinum helps the rapid reduction of cobalt oxides in hydrogen at a rather low temperature (38 &#xb0;C). In addition, reversible changes of the oxidation states of cobalt in the Co and CoPt NPs as a function of cycling oxygen pressure (in the range of millitorr to 36 Torr) are quantified and compared. The role of Pt in the process of Co reducing and oxidizing was explored. Our findings permit the prediction of the cobalt oxidation states as the reaction conditions are altered. The experimental results also suggest the presence of tetrahedral structure of Cobalt oxide that differs from the Co<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> spinel structure.</p></abstract><abstract abstract-type="graphical">
<fig fig-type="figure" id="f_tgr1" position="float">
<graphic xlink:href="nl-2010-04209c_0006.tif" id="tgr1"/></fig>
</abstract><kwd-group kwd-group-type="keywords"><kwd>In-situ X-ray absorption</kwd><kwd>Bimetallic CoPt nanoparticles</kwd><kwd>oxidation states</kwd><kwd>alloy effect</kwd><kwd>cycling pressure</kwd><kwd>octahedral and tetrahedral structure</kwd></kwd-group></article-meta><notes id="notes-1"><label>&#x22a5;</label><title>Author Contributions</title><p>These authors contributed equally to this work.</p></notes></front><body><p>Cobalt is one of the important transition metals used for catalytic hydrogenation reactions of CO and CO<sub>2</sub> to produce gaseous or liquid hydrocarbons. It has a major role to play in the industrial process with a long history of producing synthetic fuels. The reducibility of Co is important for hydrogenation reactions of CO and CO<sub>2</sub><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref1">(1)</xref> while the oxidation property is important for CO oxidation. The oxidation state of Co nanocatalysts is sensitive to the chemical environment and reaction temperature. Recently, thermodynamic phase diagram of Co oxide nanoparticles has been derived based on the surface energies of nanophase and bulk phase of Co oxides.<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref2">(2)</xref> In priniciple, the derived phase diagram predicts the most thermodynamically stable phase of Co oxide under a given chemical environment and temperature. In reality, nanoparticles of Co oxide may be trapped in a metastable phase due to kinetic barriers between the different phases. Thus, it is highly desirable to directly monitor the oxidation states of Co nanoparticles under the variable chemical environment and temperature.</p><p>To develop a molecular understanding of the chemistry of these reactions we synthesized cobalt monometallic and cobalt&#x2212;platinum bimetallic nanoparticles to study the change of the oxidation states in the different reactant gases that are chemically oxidizing (in O<sub>2</sub>) or reducing (in H<sub>2</sub>). In this paper, we report the chemical behavior of 4 nm size Co and CoPt bimetallic nanoparticles in 1 bar of hydrogen and a partial pressure range of millitorr to 36 Torr oxygen (mixed with Helium at 1 bar). We monitored the cobalt oxidation states using X-ray absorption total electron yield spectroscopy that permits recording the changes of cobalt oxidation states under in situ reaction conditions.</p><p>To our knowledge, due to the technical difficulty (balancing UHV condition for soft X-ray and chemical reaction condition), few experiments have been conducted to explore the chemical states of catalysts at different gas environments especially to the one bar pressure range with soft X-rays.<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref3 ref4">(3, 4)</xref> The 3d metal L edge soft X-ray absorption provides detailed features that can be well resolved as compared with K edge absorption.<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref5">(5)</xref> This makes soft X-ray absorption a powerful tool when exploring the oxidation states of the catalysts since the fine structure is sensitive to the oxidation states. With the rapid theoretical development in the soft X-ray region,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref5">(5)</xref> the L edge X-ray absorption calculations are also available for solid interpretation or confirmation of experimental measurements.</p><p>In situ X-ray absorption experiments were performed at the undulator beamline 7.0.1 of the Advanced Light Source (Berkeley, CA). A gas reaction cell (figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig1">1</xref>) is used to collect the total electron yield (TEY) at the pressure range from millitorr to over one bar. In X-ray absorption, soft X-ray photons promote electrons from the core level into the empty states. Each absorption event produces Auger and secondary electrons, and the total electron yield (TEY) is proportional to the number of absorption events. Different from X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS), in the TEY mode the signals are detected through a conductor (in this case a piece of inert gold foil) to the ammeter instead of electrons going through the vacuum and collected by the spectrometer. Thus this technique allows studying the electronic structure at a much higher pressure. The exploring depth of this technique is around 5 nm for metal.<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref6">(6)</xref> Nanoparticles were deposited onto a 0.1 mm thickness gold foil using the Langmuir&#x2212;Blodgett (LB, Nima Technology M611) method. Samples were characterized with transmission electron microscopy (TEM, Jeol 2100 and Philips CM300), scanning electron microscopy (SEM, Zeiss Ultra55) and X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS, home-built) prior to the synchrotron measurements.</p><p>The reaction cell is separated from UHV by a Si<sub>3</sub>N<sub>4</sub> membrane window of 1 &#xd7; 0.5 mm<sup>2</sup> in size and 100 nm in thickness. X-ray absorption at the Co L edges was recorded with 0.3 eV resolution. A cobalt sample in the UHV chamber is used for energy calibration. The gas flow was regulated by mass flow controllers (Porter Instruments, Hatfield, PA) that were connected to the flow cell. Pressure inside the reaction cell was adjusted by the valve to a turbo pump and is read by two baratron gauges installed right before and after the reaction cell along the gas flow line.</p><p>The 4 nm Pt<sub>50</sub>Co<sub>50</sub> and 4 nm Co nanoparticles were synthesized employing a modified polyol reduction protocol.<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref7">(7)</xref> PVP-capped Pt NPs synthesized under the similar reaction conditions are &#x223c;10 nm in average. To synthesize Pt<sub>50</sub>Co<sub>50</sub> NPs, Pt(acac)<sub>2</sub> and Co(acac)<sub>2</sub> metal precursor salt mixtures are reduced and conucleated at about the boiling temperature of ethylene glycol solvent. Rapid temperature ramping using an oil bath is key to the success of the synthesis in the preparation. When ramping rates slower than 20 &#xb0;C/min are employed the resulting colloidal suspension composes of inhomogeneous mixtures of monometallic platinum nanoparticles and bimetallic alloy nanoparticles with broad concentration gradients. In the absence of Pt, no nucleation of Co was observed. PVP-capped Co NPs were obtained in benzyl alchohol with 1,6-hexanediol as the reducing agent. Monometallic Co nanoparticles are magnetic and subject to oxidation as they are exposed to the air.</p><p>An array of bulk and surface techniques including TEM, scanning transmission electron microscopy (STEM)/energy dispersive spectroscopy (EDS), X-ray diffraction (XRD), and XPS were employed to characterize the as-synthesized nanoparticles. Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig2">2</xref> shows TEM images of Pt<sub>50</sub>Co<sub>50</sub> NPs with average particle sizes of 4.06 &#xb1; 0.71 nm (Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig2">2</xref>A,C). A representative high-resolution TEM (HR-TEM) image reveals lattice fringes with 0.22 nm spacings that correspond to [111] lattice of Pt<sub>50</sub>Co<sub>50</sub> in Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig2">2</xref>B. EDS spectra of multiple single particles of Pt<sub>50</sub>Co<sub>50</sub> reveal an average composition of 35 &#xb1; 10 mol % Co (<xref rid="si1">Supporting Information</xref>). Additionally, no stray monometallic nanoparticles were detected in our STEM/EDS analysis. Similarly, Co nanoparticles are 4.05 &#xb1; 1.79 nm on average (Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig2">2</xref>D,F). Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig2">2</xref>E shows a representative Co nanocrystal in the zone axis with fast Fourier transform (FFT, inset) revealing hexagonal array of atoms. SEM pictures of the LB films on Au substrates were taken on the as-prepared and postcatalysis samples of Pt<sub>50</sub>Co<sub>50</sub> nanoparticles and show 4 nm discrete nanoparticles with no significant changes in size or morphology after catalytic studies (<xref rid="si1">Supporting Information</xref> Figure S1A,B, respectively.)</p><fig fig-type="figure" id="fig1" position="float"><label>Figure 1</label><caption><p>Gas reaction cell for in situ X-ray absorption characterization. Pressure can vary from millitorr to over one bar. Temperature varies from room temperature to 300 &#xb0;C.</p></caption><graphic id="gr1" position="float" xlink:href="nl-2010-04209c_0008.tif"/></fig><fig fig-type="figure" id="fig2" position="float"><label>Figure 2</label><caption><p>TEM images of Pt<sub>50</sub>Co<sub>50</sub> NPs (A) and Co NPs (D). HR-TEM image of ca. 4 nm Pt<sub>50</sub>Co<sub>50</sub> nanoparticle showing lattice fringe (B). HR-TEM image of 4 nm Co nanoparticle with FFT image inset (E). Particle size histograms of 4 nm Pt<sub>50</sub>Co<sub>50</sub> (C) and Co NPs (F).</p></caption><graphic id="gr2" position="float" xlink:href="nl-2010-04209c_0009.tif"/></fig><p>XRD reveals a broad FCC pattern with diffraction peaks that are intermediate to the monometallic Pt and monometallic (FCC) Co. No CoO phase is discernible from the XRD pattern (<xref rid="si1">Supporting Information</xref> Figure 2B). Furthermore, Debye-Scherer analysis reveals an average particle size of 4 nm, which is also consistent with TEM size histograms. On the other hand, in the case of Co NPs the XRD pattern reveals nanocrystalline structures with coexisting metallic and oxide phases (<xref rid="si1">Supporting Information</xref> Figure S2A). Monometallic Co and bimetallic Pt<sub>50</sub>Co<sub>50</sub> nanoparticles have been studied using XPS for chemical analysis (<xref rid="si1">Supporting Information</xref> Figures S3 and S4). Because of the PVP cappings, Co 2p XPS spectra have low signal-to-noise ratio. Still one can tell that Co in the CoPt NPs is in a more reduced state since the 2p<sup>3/2</sup> peak in the CoPt NPs is at the lower binding energy (778 eV) than in the Co NPs (780 eV), which is consistent with X-ray absorption data. Au 4f spectrum in <xref rid="si1">Supporting Information</xref> Figure S4A was used for energy calibration. Pt 4f signal is of high quality and the fitting results in ca. 80% metallic Pt with the major 4f<sup>7/2</sup> peak centered at 71.5 eV (<xref rid="si1">Supporting Information</xref> Figure S4B).</p><p>The total electron yield spectra as a function of X-ray photon energy for various cobalt oxidation states are sown in Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig3">3</xref>.<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref8 ref9">(8, 9)</xref> In CoO&#x2019;s stable structure, Co<sup>2+</sup> is octahedrally coordinated with oxygen. Another stable cobalt oxide is the spinel oxide Co<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub>, which is formed under ambient room temperature and oxygen partial pressure.<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref10">(10)</xref> In Co<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub>, Co<sup>3+</sup> is octahedrally coordinated and Co<sup>2+</sup> is tetrahedrally coordinated with oxygen, where Co<sup>3+</sup>/Co<sup>2+</sup> = 2:1. Even though Co<sup>2+</sup> O<sub>h</sub> is generally regarded as the stable CoO state, in the sample spectrum shown in Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig3">3</xref> stronger feature at photon energy 778.8 than at 780.0 eV suggests the necessity to have a Co<sup>2+</sup> T<sub>d</sub> component that is independent of the spinel oxide. To quantitatively identify the oxidation states of Co in Co and CoPt nanoparticles, a least-squares fitting method is used to fit the spectra with these four references that represent known oxidation states or structures. In Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig3">3</xref>, one fitting example is given to show how one spectrum was decomposed into the four references. Since the oxidation states composition of the four references are known, the fraction of each individual oxidation state in the Co and CoPt NPs can be obtained and they are plotted in Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig6">6</xref>. It is interesting to notice that for the spectrum of CoPt NPs, the shoulder at &#x223c;777.4 eV is missing compared with the CoO reference and the spectrum of Co NPs (see Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig5">5</xref>). This difference could be caused by the change of crystallinity or variation in site symmetry<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref8">(8)</xref> that is induced by the addition of Pt to Co. The slight discrepancies between the original spectrum and the fitting between 783 and 787 eV in Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig3">3</xref> could be caused by the background subtracting or the existence of a small amount of Co hydroxide.</p><fig fig-type="figure" id="fig3" position="float"><label>Figure 3</label><caption><p>References of Co oxidation states and one example of the least-squares fitting of Co L edge spectrum with the references. Co<sup>0</sup>, Co<sup>2+</sup> O<sub>h</sub>, and Co<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> references are from ref <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref8">8</xref> and Co<sup>2+</sup> T<sub>d</sub> reference is from ref <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref9">9</xref>. Through the least-squares component fitting, fractions of Co oxidation states at each oxidizing condition were obtained.</p></caption><graphic id="gr3" position="float" xlink:href="nl-2010-04209c_0001.tif"/></fig><p>Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig4">4</xref> demonstrates the comparison of reducibility of Co in Co and CoPt NPs. All measurements were conducted at one bar of pure He or H<sub>2</sub>. With the references from refs <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref8">8</xref> and <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref9">9</xref> oxidation states of Co at the different reducing conditions can be identified. Before introducing H<sub>2</sub>, Co L edge absorption spectra were obtained in one bar He at room temperature. Co in the as-made CoPt NPs is in a more reduced state compared with Co in the as-made Co NPs. When introducing H<sub>2</sub> at 38 &#xb0;C, the Co is almost completely reduced in the CoPt NPs. While for Co in the Co NPs, one bar H<sub>2</sub> at 250 &#xb0;C still could not completely reduce Co to the metallic state. This striking different condition demonstrates that Pt facilitates effectively Co reduction in the form of bimetallic nanoparticles. Previous study on CoPt layer structure generated by spin coating also demonstrated that Pt helped to reduce Co.<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref11">(11)</xref> This can be explained as Pt is able to dissociate H<sub>2</sub> upon H<sub>2</sub> adsorption and hydrogen atoms are spilled over from Pt to Co thus makes Co much easier to reduce. An earlier study also shows the size effect on the reducibility of Co NPs,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref4">(4)</xref> where it is found that the smaller cobalt nanoparticles (3 nm) are easier to reduce than the larger nanoparticles (10 nm). Our results demonstrate a more dramatic effect on Co&#x2019;s reducibility when introducing the noble metal Pt.</p><fig fig-type="figure" id="fig4" position="float"><label>Figure 4</label><caption><p>Comparison of CoPt and Co NPs in one bar He or H<sub>2</sub> at the elevated temperatures. Co is almost completely reduced to metal at 38 &#xb0;C in the CoPt NPs while Co in pure Co NPs is only partially reduced at 250 &#xb0;C.</p></caption><graphic id="gr4" position="float" xlink:href="nl-2010-04209c_0002.tif"/></fig><p>Next, Co and CoPt NPs are studied in the oxidizing conditions. The gas is composed of He and O<sub>2</sub> with He/O<sub>2</sub> = 20:1 at 125 &#xb0;C. The total pressure is cycled from millitorr to one bar and back to millitorr while O<sub>2</sub> partial pressure is changed from millitorr to 36 Torr and back to millitorr. Co L edge absorption spectra were recorded at the same spot as well as different spots and no X-ray induced artifacts were observed.</p><p>It is not straightforward to tell at each selected O<sub>2</sub> partial pressure if the system arrived at the thermodynamically equilibrium or not. Because after the initial oxidation step, the oxidation rate can drop to a very low value.<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref12 ref13">(12, 13)</xref> Also kinetic hindrance can keep the system in a metastable state for a very long time without approaching the thermodynamical equilibrium.<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref14">(14)</xref> In our case, at each pressure point a series of spectra were taken (in the time scale of 20&#x2212;50 min) at the Co L edge until the fine structure does not change anymore, which indicates the Co arrives at a kinetically stable or metastable state. For a real catalytic reaction, the highest activity is expected to happen at the phase boundaries where the reaction is prevailed by the kinetics instead of thermodynamics.<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref15">(15)</xref></p><p>Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig5">5</xref> selects some of these series of spectra (at stabilized condition) at the different O<sub>2</sub> partial pressure and Co in the Co and CoPt NPs are compared at each pressure point. By comparing these Co L edge spectra with the reference qualitatively one can see that most time Co in the CoPt NPs is in a more reduced state than in the Co NPs. To give a more quantitative picture of the evolution of Co&#x2019;s oxidation states in the oxidizing conditions least-squares component fitting is performed with four reference spectra shown in Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig3">3</xref>. Through fitting at each pressure point, fractions of Co<sup>0</sup>, Co<sup>2+</sup>, and Co<sup>3+</sup> can be obtained on the stablilized specra of Co. Carbon K edge absorption spectra were also obtained (not shown here) in the reducing and oxidizing conditions; no significant changes in the carbon K edge absorption spectra were observed. Since the Pt-catalyzed decomposition temperature for PVP is beyond 300 &#xb0;C, at 125 &#xb0;C most PVP cappings remain intact.<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref16">(16)</xref></p><fig fig-type="figure" id="fig5" position="float"><label>Figure 5</label><caption><p>Examples of Co L edge absorption spectra obtained at the different oxidizing condition. In this study, the total pressure of He and O<sub>2</sub> is varied with fixed ratio of He/O<sub>2</sub> = 20:1 at 125 &#xb0;C. Pressures shown in the figure are the partial pressure of oxygen cycling from low to high and back to low in a range of millitorr to 36 Torr. At the same oxidizing condition, Co presents different oxidation states in the CoPt and Co NPs.</p></caption><graphic id="gr5" position="float" xlink:href="nl-2010-04209c_0003.tif"/></fig><p>Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig6">6</xref> shows that the oxidation state of Co changes with the cycling O<sub>2</sub> partial pressure for Co in both Co and CoPt NPs (The first points from left for Co and CoPt were taken in high vacuum, no gas flow). The ratio of He to O<sub>2</sub> is kept at 20:1 so the corresponding total pressures change from millitorr to one bar and decrease back to millitorr. At the lower pressure, Co is in a more reduced state in the CoPt than in the Co NPs. This is illustrated by the higher fraction of Co<sup>0</sup> and lower fraction of Co<sup>2+</sup> for Co in the CoPt NPs than in the Co NPs. At the low pressure, Co<sup>3+</sup> occupy very little or zero fraction. When the pressure is increased toward 36 Torr partial O<sub>2</sub> pressure (one bar total pressure), the fractions of Co<sup>0</sup> and Co<sup>2+</sup> for both NPs converge while the fraction of Co<sup>3+</sup> is significantly higher for Co in the Co NPs than in the CoPt NPs. When pressure is decreased from the highest point to millitorr, fractions of Co<sup>3+</sup> in both CoPt and Co are reversible, that is, drop to zero when O<sub>2</sub> partial pressure drops below 4.8 Torr; the fraction of Co<sup>0</sup> and Co<sup>2+</sup> in the CoPt NPs are partially reversible (hysteresis) while the fraction of Co<sup>0</sup> and Co<sup>2+</sup> in the Co NPs are the least reversible. Hysteresis phenomena of CO<sub>2</sub> production as a function of CO partial pressure on Pd has been studied before,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref17">(17)</xref> where the hysteresis was shown to be caused by the subsurface oxygen diffusion.</p><fig fig-type="figure" id="fig6" position="float"><label>Figure 6</label><caption><p>Fractions of Co oxidation states and average valence versus the cycling partial pressure of O<sub>2</sub> with fixed ratio He/O<sub>2</sub> = 20:1 at 125 &#xb0;C are plotted. O<sub>2</sub> pressure increases from millitorr to 36.2 Torr and then decreases back to millitorr. Co and CoPt NPs with similar size (4 nm) are compared. Co<sup>2+</sup> fraction represents the sum of Co<sup>2+</sup> O<sub>h</sub> and Co<sup>2+</sup> T<sub>d</sub> components. Individual fractions of the two Co<sup>2+</sup> structures are plotted in Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig7">7</xref>.</p></caption><graphic id="gr6" position="float" xlink:href="nl-2010-04209c_0004.tif"/></fig><p>The hysteresis phenomena in regard to the oxidation state change of Co as a function of O<sub>2</sub> partial pressure cycling may be explained similarly by the slow diffusion rate of oxygen from the surface to the subsurface. Basically, the diffusion of oxygen from the surface to subsurface is very slow so that even though there is no change from the X-ray absorption spectra the final equilibrium may not arrive in regard to the oxygen diffusion. Since during the increase and decrease of the O<sub>2</sub> partial pressure the oxygen keeps diffusing into the NPs, Co will be in a more oxidized state when O<sub>2</sub> partial pressure is decreasing than while it is increasing. On the other hand, once the pressure of oxygen is changed, significant change of Co oxidation state is observed and usually does not change after 20&#x2212;50 min. This represents an intrinsic steady state that is formed under the oxygen, Co NPs and their interface. Each spectrum shown under the new pressure corresponds to a quasi-equilibrium state while the slow diffusion of oxygen may cause the hysteresis. Other studies (and reference therein)<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref18">(18)</xref> also suggested that hysteresis was connected with stress&#x2212;strain energy associated with lattice expansion-contraction, resulting in generation-annihilation of dislocation networks, especially for small particles.</p><p>The low hysteresis (completely reversible) of Co<sup>3+</sup> state as the function of O<sub>2</sub> partial pressure implies that they are mostly formed at the surface since they are not affected by the diffusion of oxygen. Co<sup>3+</sup> oxidation state plays a very important role in the catalytic reactions. A study<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref19">(19)</xref> suggests that the active state of Co for CO oxidation reactions is Co<sup>3+</sup>. Alloying with Pt tunes the amount of Co<sup>3+</sup> state at the high pressure for Co. The reversibility of Co oxidation states with the cycling O<sub>2</sub> partial pressure demonstrates the importance of studying catalysts at the in situ conditions for those states that are catalytically active may never appear in the low pressure or UHV condition.</p><p>Previous study showed that the oxidation rate of Co increases with the increasing O<sub>2</sub> partial pressure.<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref13">(13)</xref> In our study, oxidation state stabilized relatively fast at each O<sub>2</sub> partial pressure for both Co and CoPt NPs at 125 &#xb0;C. Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig6">6</xref> shows that Pt enhances the oxidation resistance of Co at the elevated partial O<sub>2</sub> pressure. The theory of metal oxidation and alloy effect on the metal oxidation resistance was developed long ago.<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref12 ref20 ref21 ref22">(12, 20-22)</xref> Basically, for many metals in the thin film region the oxidation rate is controlled by the diffusion of metal ions to the surface as well as the electron tunneling to the surface. To apply the metal oxidation theory to our system, the possible mechanism that Pt enhanced the oxidation resistance of Co could be (1) the formation of PtO<sub>2</sub> (XPS data shows top layer Pt is oxidized) at the surface may slow down the electron tunneling rate thus slow down the oxidation of Co; (2) at the phase boundary of Pt oxide and Co oxide, metal ion diffusion or electron tunneling may slow down due to the sudden electronic potential change; and (3) alloying with Pt may generate more free electrons at the metal&#x2212;oxide interface. If that is the case, according to Wagner-Hauffe rule, these extra electrons will increase the concentration of interstitial Co vacancies, thus decrease the Co ion concentration. Since the oxidation rate is determined by the metal ion diffusion, the decrease of the Co ion concentration will decrease the oxidation rate of Co.</p><p>Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig7">7</xref> shows the evolution of fractions of tetrahedral Co<sup>2+</sup> T<sub>d</sub> and octahedral Co<sup>2+</sup> O<sub>h</sub> as a function of O<sub>2</sub> partial pressure. Overall, Co<sup>2+</sup> T<sub>d</sub> has a higher fraction in the Co than in the CoPt NPs. In both Co and CoPt NPs, the fraction of Co<sup>2+</sup> T<sub>d</sub> decreases with the increasing O<sub>2</sub> pressure and increases when the O<sub>2</sub> partial pressure goes down again, while the fraction of Co<sup>2+</sup> O<sub>h</sub> increases with the increasing pressure and decreases when the O<sub>2</sub> partial pressure goes down again except Co<sup>2+</sup> O<sub>h</sub> fraction fluctuates at the high O<sub>2</sub> partial pressure (18&#x2212;36 Torr) for the Co NPs. At 36 Torr O<sub>2</sub> partial pressure, the fraction of Co<sup>2+</sup> O<sub>h</sub> is higher in the CoPt NPs than in the Co NPs. A closer look at Figures <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig6">6</xref> and <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig7">7</xref> implies that for the Co NPs most Co<sup>3+</sup> at high pressure is transformed from the Co<sup>2+</sup> O<sub>h</sub> structure since when O<sub>2</sub> partial pressure increases from 18 to 36 Torr the fraction of Co<sup>2+</sup> O<sub>h</sub> decreases while the fraction of Co<sup>2+</sup> T<sub>d</sub> remains flat. In the CoPt NPs, Co<sup>3+</sup> may be transformed from both Co<sup>2+</sup> O<sub>h</sub> and Co<sup>2+</sup> T<sub>d</sub> structures.</p><fig fig-type="figure" id="fig7" position="float"><label>Figure 7</label><caption><p>Following Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig6">6</xref>, fractions of octahedral Co<sup>2+</sup> O<sub>h</sub> and tetrahedral Co<sup>2+</sup> T<sub>d</sub> versus partial pressure of O<sub>2</sub> with fixed ratio He/O<sub>2</sub> = 20:1 at 125 &#xb0;C. O<sub>2</sub> pressure increases from millitorr to 36.2 Torr and then decreases back to millitorr. Co and CoPt NPs with similar size (4 nm) are compared.</p></caption><graphic id="gr7" position="float" xlink:href="nl-2010-04209c_0005.tif"/></fig><p>Generally the stable state for Co in CoO is Co<sup>2+</sup> O<sub>h</sub> structure while the fitting implies there may be some Co<sup>2+</sup> T<sub>d</sub> structure in the 4 nm nanoparticles that is independent of Co<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> spinel structure. A previous study<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref5">(5)</xref> found that Co in the Pt&#x2212;Co cathode is oxidized to Co<sup>2+</sup> T<sub>d</sub> and was explained by cobalt atoms coordinating with fluorine atoms from the Nafion ionomer. Stable Co<sup>2+</sup> T<sub>d</sub> structure with oxygen was also found in Zn<sub>0.95</sub>Co<sub>0.05</sub>O compound.<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref23">(23)</xref> Here, in our case the component fitting on the 4 nm nanoparticles suggests that Co<sup>2+</sup> is stabilized to a tetrahedrally coordinated structure in addition to the Co<sup>2+</sup> O<sub>h</sub> structure. It is also possible that the interaction between the Co and the PVP cappings keeps Co<sup>2+</sup> T<sub>d</sub> more stable. A definite conclusion calls for a calculation of the oxidized nanoparticle&#x2019;s structure under the O<sub>2</sub> partial pressure. Previous studies suggest Co<sup>3+</sup> and Co<sup>2+</sup> O<sub>h</sub> is active and Co<sup>2+</sup> T<sub>d</sub> in the spinel is almost inactive for CO oxidation;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref24 ref25">(24, 25)</xref> mapping the oxidation states distribution will help optimize the reaction condition for enhanced catalytic performance.</p><p>From a more fundamental point of view, observing the evolution of oxidation states of metal under the gas pressure provides invaluable information for understanding the gas&#x2212;solid interface. Depending on the system, oxidation of surface can either lead to an active or inactive phase of the catalyst.<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref26 ref27">(26, 27)</xref> It is relevant to investigate the factors that may affect the ease or resistance of oxide formation, in this case the alloy effect. During the reaction, the surface is under the adsorption and desorption processes and is in equilibrium with the gas phase. K. Reuter et al. showed that the surface free energy is dependent only on the gas phase chemical potential.<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref15 ref27">(15, 27)</xref> By relating the gas phase chemical potential to the total energy that was obtainable from the density functional theory (DFT) calculation, a surface phase diagram of stable and metastable structures of RuO<sub>2</sub> in the chemical potential space was presented.<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref15 ref28">(15, 28)</xref> Surface phase boundary was shown to span from UHV to more than one atmosphere pressure, where strong kinetic effect may lead to high catalytic activity. Also surface X-ray diffraction (SXRD) and first-principle calculations were performed to demonstrate that at the different oxygen partial pressure the metal presented different oxidized phases,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref14">(14)</xref> where the experiment also showed a kinetic hindrance during the oxidation of Pd(100) that was not able to be revealed by the DFT calculation. Thus the feedback between the experiment and the DFT calculation complete each other and lead to the correct description of the system. Specifically, the experimental exploration of the chemical state phase diagram as a function of chemical potential or pressure would aid the DFT calculations under the H<sub>2</sub> and O<sub>2</sub> gas environments. Overall investigating the catalyst oxidation state in situ is important because the gas phase chemical reactivity plays a dominant role in deciding the stable oxidation states.</p><p>To summarize, in situ X-ray absorption total electron yield experiments were performed on 4 nm Co and CoPt NPs and fractions of Co oxidation states were mapped under the cycling total pressure from millitorr to one bar. Reducibility and oxidation states of Co in Co and CoPt NPs were compared. Pt has a substantial impact on the oxidation state and structure of Co. Co is much easier to reduce when alloying with Pt. Pt keeps Co in a more reduced state in the low O<sub>2</sub> partial pressure range. When O<sub>2</sub> partial pressure is increased above 4.8 Torr, Co<sup>0</sup> and Co<sup>2+</sup> fractions in the Co and CoPt NPs tend to converge while Co has a much larger amount of Co<sup>3+</sup> fraction in the Co NPs. Hysteresis phenomena were observed for the evolution of the oxidation states as the O<sub>2</sub> partial pressure was cycled. Our study also suggests that a stable tetrahedral Co<sup>2+</sup> T<sub>d</sub> oxide structure exist and evolve together with the octahedral Co<sup>2+</sup> O<sub>h</sub> oxide structure under the O<sub>2</sub> environment. Catalytic properties of monometallic and bimetallic nanoparticles of Co are closely related to the oxidation state of Co. By in situ mapping the oxidation states of Co at various redox conditions, information toward understanding the catalytic reactivity of Co nanoparticles is provided.</p></body><back><notes id="afn2"><label>#</label><title>Author Present Address</title><p>Department of Physics, Tamkang University, Tamsui, Taiwan 250, Republic of China.</p></notes><ack><title>Acknowledgment</title><p>We thank the help from Mark West and Gideon Jones for designing and building the reaction cell. Dr. Peng Jiang and Dr. Ferenc Borondics from Professor Miquel Salmeron&#x2019;s group provided advice in many experimental details. Also we want to thank Wei-cheng Wang for his help at beamline 7 in ALS. This work was supported by the Director, Office of Energy Research, Office of Basic Energy Sciences of the U.S. Department of Energy under Contract DE-AC02-05CH11231. The Advanced Light Source is supported by the Director, Office of Science, Office of Basic Energy Sciences, of the U.S. Department of Energy under Contract No. DE-AC02-05CH11231. National Center for Electron Microscopy, Lawrence Berkeley Lab, is supported by the U.S. Department of Energy under Contract no. DE-AC02-05CH11231. Molecular Foundry is supported by the Director, Office of Science, Office of Basic Energy Sciences, Division of Material Sciences and Engineering, of the U.S. Department of Energy under Contract no. DE-AC02-05CH11231.</p></ack><notes id="si1" notes-type="si">
<title><inline-supplementary-material xlink:href="/doi/suppl/10.1021/nl104209c">Supporting Information</inline-supplementary-material></title><p>Experimental procedures and additional figures. This material is available free of charge via the Internet at <uri xlink:href="http://pubs.acs.org">http://pubs.acs.org</uri>.</p></notes><ref-list><title>References</title><ref id="ref1"><label>1. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit1"><name><surname>Khodakov</surname><x>, </x><given-names>A. Y.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Chu</surname><x>, </x><given-names>W.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Fongarland</surname><x>, </x><given-names>P.</given-names></name><article-title>Advances in the Development of Novel Cobalt Fischer&#x2212;Tropsch Catalysts for Synthesis of Long-Chain Hydrocarbons and Clean Fuels</article-title><source>Chem. Rev.</source><x> </x><year>2007</year><x>, </x><volume>107</volume><x> (</x><issue>5</issue><x>) </x><fpage>1692</fpage><x>&ndash;</x><lpage>1744</lpage></citation></ref><ref id="ref2"><label>2. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit2"><name><surname>Navrotsky</surname><x>, </x><given-names>A.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Ma</surname><x>, </x><given-names>C. C.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Lilova</surname><x>, </x><given-names>K.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Birkner</surname><x>, </x><given-names>N.</given-names></name><article-title>Nanophase Transition Metal Oxides Show Large Thermodynamically Driven Shifts in Oxidation-Reduction Equilibria</article-title><source>Science</source><x> </x><year>2010</year><x>, </x><volume>330</volume><x> (</x><issue>6001</issue><x>) </x><fpage>199</fpage><x>&ndash;</x><lpage>201</lpage></citation></ref><ref id="ref3"><label>3. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit3"><name><surname>Forsberg</surname><x>, </x><given-names>J.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Duda</surname><x>, </x><given-names>L. C.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Olsson</surname><x>, </x><given-names>A.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Schmitt</surname><x>, </x><given-names>T.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Andersson</surname><x>, </x><given-names>J.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Nordgren</surname><x>, </x><given-names>J.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Hedberg</surname><x>, </x><given-names>J.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Leygraf</surname><x>, </x><given-names>C.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Aastrup</surname><x>, </x><given-names>T.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Wallinder</surname><x>, </x><given-names>D.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Guo</surname><x>, </x><given-names>J. H.</given-names></name><article-title>System for in situ studies of atmospheric corrosion of metal films using soft x-ray spectroscopy and quartz crystal microbalance</article-title><source>Rev. Sci. Instrum.</source><x> </x><year>2007</year><x>, </x><volume>78</volume><x> (</x><issue>8</issue><x>) </x><fpage>083110</fpage></citation></ref><ref id="ref4"><label>4. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit4"><name><surname>Herranz</surname><x>, </x><given-names>T.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Deng</surname><x>, </x><given-names>X. Y.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Cabot</surname><x>, </x><given-names>A.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Guo</surname><x>, </x><given-names>J. G.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Salmeron</surname><x>, </x><given-names>M.</given-names></name><article-title>Influence of the Cobalt Particle Size in the CO Hydrogenation Reaction Studied by In Situ X-ray Absorption Spectroscopy</article-title><source>J. Phys. Chem. B</source><x> </x><year>2009</year><x>, </x><volume>113</volume><x> (</x><issue>31</issue><x>) </x><fpage>10721</fpage><x>&ndash;</x><lpage>10727</lpage></citation></ref><ref id="ref5"><label>5. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit5"><name><surname>Bazin</surname><x>, </x><given-names>D.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Guczi</surname><x>, </x><given-names>L.</given-names></name><article-title>Soft X-ray absorption spectroscopy in heterogeneous catalysis</article-title><source>Appl. Catal., A</source><x> </x><year>2001</year><x>, </x><volume>213</volume><x> (</x><issue>2</issue><x>) </x><fpage>147</fpage><x>&ndash;</x><lpage>162</lpage></citation></ref><ref id="ref6"><label>6. </label><citation citation-type="book" id="cit6"><person-group person-group-type="allauthors"><name><surname>Sto&#x308;hr</surname><x>, </x><given-names>J.</given-names></name></person-group><source>NEXAFS Spectroscopy</source>; <publisher-name>Springer Verlag</publisher-name>: <publisher-loc>New York</publisher-loc>,<x> </x><year>1996</year>.</citation></ref><ref id="ref7"><label>7. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit7"><name><surname>Yu</surname><x>, </x><given-names>W. Y.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Wang</surname><x>, </x><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Liu</surname><x>, </x><given-names>H. F.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Zheng</surname><x>, </x><given-names>W.</given-names></name><article-title>Preparation and characterization of polymer-protected Pt/Co bimetallic colloids and their catalytic properties in the selective hydrogenation of cinnamaldehyde</article-title><source>J. Mol. Catal A: Chem.</source><x> </x><year>1996</year><x>, </x><volume>112</volume><x> (</x><issue>1</issue><x>) </x><fpage>105</fpage><x>&ndash;</x><lpage>113</lpage></citation></ref><ref id="ref8"><label>8. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit8"><name><surname>Morales</surname><x>, </x><given-names>F.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>de Groot</surname><x>, </x><given-names>F. M. F.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Glatzel</surname><x>, </x><given-names>P.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Kleimenov</surname><x>, </x><given-names>E.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Bluhm</surname><x>, </x><given-names>H.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Havecker</surname><x>, </x><given-names>M.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Knop-Gericke</surname><x>, </x><given-names>A.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Weckhuysen</surname><x>, </x><given-names>B. M.</given-names></name><article-title>In Situ X-ray Absorption of Co/Mn/TiO<sub>2</sub> Catalysts for Fischer&#x2212;Tropsch Synthesis</article-title><source>J. Phys. Chem. B</source><x> </x><year>2004</year><x>, </x><volume>108</volume><x> (</x><issue>41</issue><x>) </x><fpage>16201</fpage><x>&ndash;</x><lpage>16207</lpage></citation></ref><ref id="ref9"><label>9. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit9"><name><surname>Kobayashi</surname><x>, </x><given-names>M.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Hidai</surname><x>, </x><given-names>S.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Niwa</surname><x>, </x><given-names>H.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Harada</surname><x>, </x><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Oshima</surname><x>, </x><given-names>M.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Horikawa</surname><x>, </x><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Tokushima</surname><x>, </x><given-names>T.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Shin</surname><x>, </x><given-names>S.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Nakamori</surname><x>, </x><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Aoki</surname><x>, </x><given-names>T.</given-names></name><article-title>Co oxidation accompanied by degradation of Pt-Co alloy cathode catalysts in polymer electrolyte fuel cells</article-title><source>Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys.</source><x> </x><year>2009</year><x>, </x><volume>11</volume><x> (</x><issue>37</issue><x>) </x><fpage>8226</fpage><x>&ndash;</x><lpage>8230</lpage></citation></ref><ref id="ref10"><label>10. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit10"><name><surname>Petitto</surname><x>, </x><given-names>S. C.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Marsh</surname><x>, </x><given-names>E. M.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Carson</surname><x>, </x><given-names>G. A.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Langell</surname><x>, </x><given-names>M. A.</given-names></name><article-title>Cobalt oxide surface chemistry: The interaction of CoO(100), Co<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub>(110) and Co<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub>(111) with oxygen and water</article-title><source>J. Mol. Catal A: Chem.</source><x> </x><year>2008</year><x>, </x><volume>281</volume><x> (</x><issue>1&#x2212;2</issue><x>) </x><fpage>49</fpage><x>&ndash;</x><lpage>58</lpage></citation></ref><ref id="ref11"><label>11. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit11"><name><surname>Borgna</surname><x>, </x><given-names>A.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Anderson</surname><x>, </x><given-names>B. G.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Saib</surname><x>, </x><given-names>A. M.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Bluhm</surname><x>, </x><given-names>H.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Havecker</surname><x>, </x><given-names>M.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Knop-Gericke</surname><x>, </x><given-names>A.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Kuiper</surname><x>, </x><given-names>A. E. T.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Tamminga</surname><x>, </x><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Niemantsverdriet</surname><x>, </x><given-names>J. W.</given-names></name><article-title>Pt-CO/SiO<sub>2</sub> Bimetallic Planar Model Catalysts for Selective Hydrogenation of Crotonaldehyde</article-title><source>J. Phys. Chem. B</source><x> </x><year>2004</year><x>, </x><volume>108</volume><x> (</x><issue>46</issue><x>) </x><fpage>17905</fpage><x>&ndash;</x><lpage>17914</lpage></citation></ref><ref id="ref12"><label>12. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit12"><name><surname>Cabrera</surname><x>, </x><given-names>N.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Mott</surname><x>, </x><given-names>N. F.</given-names></name><article-title>Theory of the Oxidation of Metals</article-title><source>Rep. Prog. Phys.</source><x> </x><year>1948</year><x>, </x><volume>12</volume><x>, </x><fpage>163</fpage><x>&ndash;</x><lpage>184</lpage></citation></ref><ref id="ref13"><label>13. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit13"><name><surname>Chernavskii</surname><x>, </x><given-names>P. A.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Pankina</surname><x>, </x><given-names>G. V.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Chernavskii</surname><x>, </x><given-names>A. P.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Peskov</surname><x>, </x><given-names>N. V.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Afanas&#x2019;ev</surname><x>, </x><given-names>P. V.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Perov</surname><x>, </x><given-names>N. S.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Tennov</surname><x>, </x><given-names>V. A.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Lunin</surname><x>, </x><given-names>V. V.</given-names></name><article-title>The kinetics of low-temperature oxidation of cobalt nanoparticles on a carbon carrier</article-title><source>Russ. J. Phys. Chem.</source><x> </x><year>2006</year><x>, </x><volume>80</volume><x> (</x><issue>9</issue><x>) </x><fpage>1475</fpage><x>&ndash;</x><lpage>1480</lpage></citation></ref><ref id="ref14"><label>14. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit14"><name><surname>Lundgren</surname><x>, </x><given-names>E.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Gustafson</surname><x>, </x><given-names>J.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Mikkelsen</surname><x>, </x><given-names>A.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Andersen</surname><x>, </x><given-names>J. N.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Stierle</surname><x>, </x><given-names>A.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Dosch</surname><x>, </x><given-names>H.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Todorova</surname><x>, </x><given-names>M.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Rogal</surname><x>, </x><given-names>J.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Reuter</surname><x>, </x><given-names>K.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Scheffler</surname><x>, </x><given-names>M.</given-names></name><article-title>Kinetic hindrance during the initial oxidation of Pd(100) at ambient pressures</article-title><source>Phys. Rev. Lett.</source><x> </x><year>2004</year><x>, </x><volume>92</volume><x> (</x><issue>4</issue><elocation-id>046101</elocation-id></citation></ref><ref id="ref15"><label>15. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit15"><name><surname>Reuter</surname><x>, </x><given-names>K.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Scheffler</surname><x>, </x><given-names>M.</given-names></name><article-title>Composition and structure of the RuO2(110) surface in an O-2 and CO environment: Implications for the catalytic formation of CO<sub>2</sub></article-title><source>Phys. Rev. B</source><x> </x><year>2003</year><x>, </x><volume>68</volume><x> (</x><issue>4</issue><elocation-id>045407</elocation-id></citation></ref><ref id="ref16"><label>16. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit16"><name><surname>Borodko</surname><x>, </x><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Habas</surname><x>, </x><given-names>S. E.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Koebel</surname><x>, </x><given-names>M.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Yang</surname><x>, </x><given-names>P. D.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Frei</surname><x>, </x><given-names>H.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Somorjai</surname><x>, </x><given-names>G. A.</given-names></name><article-title>Probing the Interaction of Poly(vinylpyrrolidone) with Platinum Nanocrystals by UV-Raman and FTIR</article-title><source>J. Phys. Chem. B</source><x> </x><year>2006</year><x>, </x><volume>110</volume><x> (</x><issue>46</issue><x>) </x><fpage>23052</fpage><x>&ndash;</x><lpage>23059</lpage></citation></ref><ref id="ref17"><label>17. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit17"><name><surname>Ladas</surname><x>, </x><given-names>S.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Imbihl</surname><x>, </x><given-names>R.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Ertl</surname><x>, </x><given-names>G.</given-names></name><article-title>Kinetic Oscillations during the Catalytic Co Oxidation on Pd(110) - the Role of Subsurface Oxygen</article-title><source>Surf. Sci.</source><x> </x><year>1989</year><x>, </x><volume>219</volume><x> (</x><issue>1&#x2212;2</issue><x>) </x><fpage>88</fpage><x>&ndash;</x><lpage>106</lpage></citation></ref><ref id="ref18"><label>18. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit18"><name><surname>Salomonsson</surname><x>, </x><given-names>P.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Johansson</surname><x>, </x><given-names>S.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Kasemo</surname><x>, </x><given-names>B.</given-names></name><article-title>Methane Oxidation over Pdox - on the Mechanism for the Hysteresis in Activity and Oxygen-Content</article-title><source>Catal. Lett.</source><x> </x><year>1995</year><x>, </x><volume>33</volume><x> (</x><issue>1&#x2212;2</issue><x>) </x><fpage>1</fpage><x>&ndash;</x><lpage>13</lpage></citation></ref><ref id="ref19"><label>19. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit19"><name><surname>Jansson</surname><x>, </x><given-names>J.</given-names></name><article-title>Low-temperature CO oxidation over Co<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub>/Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub></article-title><source>J. Catal.</source><x> </x><year>2000</year><x>, </x><volume>194</volume><x> (</x><issue>1</issue><x>) </x><fpage>55</fpage><x>&ndash;</x><lpage>60</lpage></citation></ref><ref id="ref20"><label>20. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit20"><name><surname>Mott</surname><x>, </x><given-names>N. F.</given-names></name><article-title>The theory of the formation of protective oxide films on metals, II</article-title><source>Trans. Faraday Soc.</source><x> </x><year>1940</year><x>, </x><volume>35</volume><x> (</x><issue>3</issue><x>) </x><fpage>0472</fpage><x>&ndash;</x><lpage>0482</lpage></citation></ref><ref id="ref21"><label>21. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit21"><name><surname>Wagner</surname><x>, </x><given-names>C.</given-names></name><article-title>Theoretical Analysis of the Diffusion Processes Determining the Oxidation Rate of Alloys</article-title><source>J. Electrochem. Soc.</source><x> </x><year>1952</year><x>, </x><volume>99</volume><x> (</x><issue>10</issue><x>) </x><fpage>369</fpage><x>&ndash;</x><lpage>380</lpage></citation></ref><ref id="ref22"><label>22. </label><citation citation-type="book" id="cit22"><person-group person-group-type="allauthors"><name><surname>Hauffe</surname><x>, </x><given-names>K.</given-names></name></person-group><source>Oxidation of Metals</source>; <publisher-name>Plenum</publisher-name>: <publisher-loc>New York</publisher-loc>,<x> </x><year>1965</year>.</citation></ref><ref id="ref23"><label>23. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit23"><name><surname>Kobayashi</surname><x>, </x><given-names>M.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Ishida</surname><x>, </x><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Hwang</surname><x>, </x><given-names>J. I.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Mizokawa</surname><x>, </x><given-names>T.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Fujimori</surname><x>, </x><given-names>A.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Mamiya</surname><x>, </x><given-names>K.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Okamoto</surname><x>, </x><given-names>J.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Takeda</surname><x>, </x><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Okane</surname><x>, </x><given-names>T.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Saitoh</surname><x>, </x><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Muramatsu</surname><x>, </x><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Tanaka</surname><x>, </x><given-names>A.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Saeki</surname><x>, </x><given-names>H.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Tabata</surname><x>, </x><given-names>H.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Kawai</surname><x>, </x><given-names>T.</given-names></name><article-title>Characterization of magnetic components in the diluted magnetic semiconductor Zn1-xCoxO by X-ray magnetic circular dichroism</article-title><source>Phys. Rev. B</source><x> </x><year>2005</year><x>, </x><volume>72</volume><x> (</x><issue>20</issue><elocation-id>201201</elocation-id></citation></ref><ref id="ref24"><label>24. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit24"><name><surname>Jansson</surname><x>, </x><given-names>J.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Palmqvist</surname><x>, </x><given-names>A. E. C.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Fridell</surname><x>, </x><given-names>E.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Skoglundh</surname><x>, </x><given-names>M.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Osterlund</surname><x>, </x><given-names>L.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Thormahlen</surname><x>, </x><given-names>P.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Langer</surname><x>, </x><given-names>V.</given-names></name><article-title>On the catalytic activity of Co<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> in low-temperature CO oxidation</article-title><source>J. Catal.</source><x> </x><year>2002</year><x>, </x><volume>211</volume><x> (</x><issue>2</issue><x>) </x><fpage>387</fpage><x>&ndash;</x><lpage>397</lpage></citation></ref><ref id="ref25"><label>25. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit25"><name><surname>Yao</surname><x>, </x><given-names>H. C.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Shelef</surname><x>, </x><given-names>M.</given-names></name><article-title>Nitric-Oxide and Carbon-Monoxide Chemisorption on Cobalt-Containing Spinels</article-title><source>J. Phys. Chem.</source><x> </x><year>1974</year><x>, </x><volume>78</volume><x> (</x><issue>24</issue><x>) </x><fpage>2490</fpage><x>&ndash;</x><lpage>2496</lpage></citation></ref><ref id="ref26"><label>26. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit26"><name><surname>Over</surname><x>, </x><given-names>H.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Kim</surname><x>, </x><given-names>Y. D.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Seitsonen</surname><x>, </x><given-names>A. P.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Wendt</surname><x>, </x><given-names>S.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Lundgren</surname><x>, </x><given-names>E.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Schmid</surname><x>, </x><given-names>M.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Varga</surname><x>, </x><given-names>P.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Morgante</surname><x>, </x><given-names>A.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Ertl</surname><x>, </x><given-names>G.</given-names></name><article-title>Atomic-scale structure and catalytic reactivity of the RuO<sub>2</sub>(110) Surface</article-title><source>Science</source><x> </x><year>2000</year><x>, </x><volume>287</volume><x> (</x><issue>5457</issue><x>) </x><fpage>1474</fpage><x>&ndash;</x><lpage>1476</lpage></citation></ref><ref id="ref27"><label>27. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit27"><name><surname>Hendriksen</surname><x>, </x><given-names>B. L. M.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Frenken</surname><x>, </x><given-names>J. W. M.</given-names></name><article-title>CO oxidation on Pt(110): Scanning tunneling microscopy inside a high-pressure flow reactor</article-title><source>Phys. Rev. Lett.</source><x> </x><year>2002</year><x>, </x><volume>89</volume><x> (</x><issue>4</issue><elocation-id>046101</elocation-id></citation></ref><ref id="ref28"><label>28. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit28"><name><surname>Reuter</surname><x>, </x><given-names>K.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Scheffler</surname><x>, </x><given-names>M.</given-names></name><article-title>Composition, structure, and stability of RuO<sub>2</sub>(110) as a function of oxygen pressure</article-title><source>Phys. Rev. B</source><x> </x><year>2002</year><x>, </x><volume>65</volume><x> (</x><issue>3</issue><elocation-id>035406</elocation-id></citation></ref></ref-list></back></article>