<?xml version="1.0" encoding="US-ASCII"?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//Atypon//DTD Archiving and Interchange DTD Suite with ACHS extensions v2.2 20080601//EN" "archivearticle.dtd">
<article article-type="research-article" dtd-version="2.2" xml:lang="EN"  xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><front><journal-meta>
<journal-id journal-id-type="publisher">ancac3</journal-id><journal-title>ACS Nano</journal-title><abbrev-journal-title abbrev-type="publisher">ACS Nano</abbrev-journal-title><issn pub-type="ppub">1936-0851</issn><issn pub-type="epub">1936-086X</issn><publisher><publisher-name>American Chemical Society</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/nn405943z</article-id><article-categories>
<subj-group subj-group-type="type-of-article">
<subject>Article</subject>
</subj-group>
</article-categories>
<title-group>
<article-title>Ternary Hybrid Nanoparticle Isomers: Directing the Nucleation of Ag on Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> Using a Solid-State Protecting Group</article-title>
</title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author" id="ath1"><name><given-names>James M.</given-names><x> </x><surname>Hodges</surname></name><x>, </x></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" id="ath2"><name><given-names>Adam J.</given-names><x> </x><surname>Biacchi</surname></name><x>, and </x></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes" id="ath3"><name><given-names>Raymond E.</given-names><x> </x><surname>Schaak</surname></name><xref ref-type="corresp" rid="cor1">*</xref><x> </x></contrib><aff id="aff1">Department of Chemistry and Materials Research Institute, <institution>The Pennsylvania State University</institution>, University Park, Pennsylvania 16802, United States</aff></contrib-group><author-notes><corresp id="cor1"><label>*</label>Address correspondence to <email xlink:href="schaak@chem.psu.edu">schaak@chem.psu.edu</email>.</corresp></author-notes><pub-date pub-type="ppub"><day>28</day><month>01</month><year>2014</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>20</day><month>12</month><year>2013</year></pub-date><volume>8</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>1047</fpage><lpage>1055</lpage><supplementary-material xlink:href="nn405943z_si_001.pdf" id="sifile1"/>
<history><date date-type="received"><day>16</day><month>11</month><year>2013</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>13</day><month>12</month><year>2013</year></date><date date-type="asap"><day>20</day><month>12</month><year>2013</year></date><date date-type="issue-pub"><day>28</day><month>01</month><year>2014</year></date><date date-type="just-accepted"><day>13</day><month>12</month><year>2013</year></date></history><permissions><copyright-statement>&copy; 2013 American Chemical Society</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2013</copyright-year><copyright-holder>American Chemical Society</copyright-holder></permissions><related-article related-article-type="pdf" xlink:href="nn405943z.pdf"/>
<abstract><p>Colloidal hybrid nanoparticles are an important class of materials that incorporate multiple nanoparticles into a single system through solid-state interfaces, which can result in multifunctionality and the emergence of synergistic properties not found in the individual components. These hybrid structures are typically produced using seeded-growth methods, where preformed nanoparticles serve as seeds onto which additional domains are added through subsequent reactions. For hybrid nanoparticles that contain more than two domains, multiple configurations with distinct connectivities and functionalities are possible, and these can be considered as nanoparticle analogues of molecular isomers. However, accessing one isomer relative to others in the same hybrid nanoparticle system is challenging, particularly when the formation of a target isomer is disfavored relative to more stable or synthetically accessible configurations. Here, we show that an iron oxide shell installed onto the Pt domain of Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> hybrid nanoparticles serves as a solid-state protecting group that can direct the nucleation of a third domain to an otherwise disfavored site. Under traditional conditions, Ag nucleates exclusively onto the Pt domain of Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterodimers, resulting in the formation of the Ag&#x2013;Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterotrimer isomer. When the Pt surface is covered with an iron oxide protecting group, the nucleation of Ag is redirected onto the Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> domain, producing the distinct and otherwise inaccessible Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub>&#x2013;Ag isomer. Similar results are obtained for the Au&#x2013;Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> system, where formation of the favored Au&#x2013;Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> configuration is blocked by the iron oxide protecting group. The thickness of the iron oxide shell that protects the Pt domain can be systematically tuned by adjusting the ratio of oleic acid to iron pentacarbonyl during the synthesis of the Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterodimers, and this insight is important for controllably implementing the protecting group chemistry.</p></abstract><abstract abstract-type="graphical">
<fig fig-type="figure" id="f_tgr1" position="float">
<graphic xlink:href="nn-2013-05943z_0008.tif" id="tgr1"/></fig>
</abstract><kwd-group><kwd>colloidal hybrid nanoparticles</kwd><kwd>nanoparticle synthesis</kwd><kwd>nanocrystals</kwd><kwd>Pt&#x2212;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub></kwd><kwd>heterodimers</kwd><kwd>heterotrimers</kwd><kwd>seeded growth</kwd><kwd>protecting group</kwd><kwd>nanoparticle isomers</kwd></kwd-group></article-meta></front><body><sec id="sec1"><title/><p>Colloidal hybrid nanoparticles integrate multiple nanoscale domains into one system that can exhibit properties not found in the individual components. These synergistic qualities are a result of electronic and magnetic communication at the solid-state heterojunctions within these structures.<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref1 ref2 ref3 ref4 ref5 ref6 ref7 ref8 ref9">(1-9)</xref> At the nanoscale, these interfacial properties are not always confined to the domain boundary and can pervade throughout the material, resulting in properties not attainable in the bulk. Additionally, careful arrangement of constituent domains can lead to cooperative processes within the particles that facilitate enhanced functionality.<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref10 ref11">(10, 11)</xref> For these reasons, hybrid nanomaterials are excellent candidates for applications in solar energy conversion,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref12 ref13">(12, 13)</xref> heterogeneous catalysis,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref14 ref15">(14, 15)</xref> magnetism,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref16">(16)</xref> electronics,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref17">(17)</xref> and biomedical imaging.<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref18">(18)</xref></p><p>Although numerous methods have been demonstrated to be effective for producing hybrid nanoparticles, the multistep seeded growth approach is among the most common due to its versatility in a wide variety of systems.<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref10 ref19 ref20 ref21">(10, 19-21)</xref> In this strategy, preformed nanocrystals are used as seeds for adding additional domains, in a stepwise manner, through subsequent reactions.<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref21">(21)</xref> As the applications of hybrid nanoparticles continue to expand and become more sophisticated, their materials requirements are becoming more explicit and rigid, particularly with respect to the types and sequences of materials linkages in higher-order systems containing more than two domains. Using an arbitrary nanoparticle heterotrimer as an example, the nucleation of a third domain (C) onto a preformed A&#x2013;B heterodimer could lead to several distinct configurations, including A&#x2013;B&#x2013;C and C&#x2013;A&#x2013;B linkages. These distinct configurations, A&#x2013;B&#x2013;C and C&#x2013;A&#x2013;B, can be considered as nanoparticle analogues of molecular isomers, because each contains the same materials but with distinct connectivities and consequently different functionalities.</p><p>Controlling such domain arrangements in hybrid nanoparticle systems is important across a wide range of applications. For example, photocatalytic water splitting can be enabled by specific configurations of semiconducting and metal nanoparticles that are designed to absorb incident photons and convert them into separated electron&#x2013;hole pairs.<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref22">(22)</xref> The necessary interfacial electron transfer processes are best facilitated by one particular sequence of material linkages, and therefore efficiency is greatest when the yield of the desired configuration is maximized, since other configurations are less active or inactive. Likewise, specific domain arrangements in optical heterostructures can modulate changes in absorbance and emission phenomena. For example, the photoluminescence efficiency of CdS quantum dots is increased when they are in close proximity to plasmonic nanoparticles,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref23 ref24">(23, 24)</xref> but emission can be quenched when there is direct contact.<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref25">(25)</xref> Since the relative locations of nanoparticle domains define the connectivity and consequent functionality of a hybrid nanoparticle, synthetic tools that permit site-specific nucleation and that provide access to the targeted configurations in high yields are therefore essential.<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref26">(26)</xref></p><p>As a route to colloidal hybrid nanoparticles, heterogeneous seeded nucleation is typically either nonselective, resulting in overgrowth on all domains, or highly selective, resulting in the exclusive formation of one specific isomer relative to others that may be preferred for a particular application. For example, Ag has been shown to nucleate only on the Pt domain of Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> hybrid nanoparticles, forming exclusively the Ag&#x2013;Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> isomer (rather than, for example, Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub>&#x2013;Ag) despite the accessibility of the Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> surface and the known affinity of Ag to also nucleate on Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> nanoparticles.<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref21">(21)</xref> For molecules, one can often direct reactivity to one particular functional group when multiple ones are accessible by installing a protecting group to block access to the undesired location while leaving the desired functional group exposed. A nanoparticle analogue of molecular protecting group chemistry would be a powerful addition to the &#x201c;total synthesis toolbox&#x201d;<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref21 ref27">(21, 27)</xref> for constructing high-order colloidal hybrid nanoparticles controllably and in high yield.</p><p>Accordingly, here we provide a proof-of-concept demonstration, for a model system, that a thin amorphous iron oxide shell can serve as a solid-state protecting group in colloidal hybrid nanoparticles to facilitate controllable regioselective nucleation and the predictable formation of distinct ternary (heterotrimer) isomers. Specifically, we show that both Ag&#x2013;Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> and Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub>&#x2013;Ag can be accessed in high yield by directing the nucleation of Ag nanoparticles selectively to either the Pt or Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> domains of Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterodimers. The propensity for Ag to nucleate on the Pt domain of Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> can be overcome by growing a thin amorphous iron oxide shell on the Pt domain as a protecting group, effectively blocking the Pt surface. This results in the nucleation of Ag on the Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> domain, forming the otherwise disfavored Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub>&#x2013;Ag isomer. The iron oxide protecting group also blocks the Pt domain from nucleating other nanoparticles, such as Au. Finally, in-depth investigations into the reaction conditions that lead to the formation of the iron oxide shell provide detailed guidelines for reproducibly applying this solid-state protecting group to hybrid nanoparticle systems.</p></sec><sec id="sec2"><title>Results and Discussion</title><sec id="sec2.1"><title>Selective Synthesis of Ag&#x2013;Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> and Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub>&#x2013;Ag Hybrid Nanoparticle Isomers</title><p>Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterodimers were synthesized by decomposing Fe(CO)<sub>5</sub> in the presence of Pt seeds, as described previously.<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref28">(28)</xref> A representative TEM image of the resulting Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterodimers is shown in <xref rid="fig1">Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig1">1</xref></xref>a, along with a STEM-EDS line scan (<xref rid="fig1">Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig1">1</xref></xref>b) showing the distribution of Pt and Fe (<italic>via</italic> the Pt M-shell and Fe K-shell transitions) across a representative Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterodimer. Both Fe and Pt are present at the Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> interface (because Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> partially envelopes the Pt domain), but the Fe signal decreases rapidly as the Pt signal increases, with near-baseline Fe signal at the outer edge of the Pt domain.</p><p>As a control experiment, when the Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterodimers from <xref rid="fig1">Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig1">1</xref></xref>a react with Ag(C<sub>2</sub>H<sub>3</sub>O<sub>2</sub>) in toluene at 60 &#xb0;C, Ag nanoparticles nucleate exclusively on the Pt domain to form Ag&#x2013;Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterotrimers.<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref21">(21)</xref> A representative TEM image of the Ag&#x2013;Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterotrimers is shown in <xref rid="fig1">Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig1">1</xref></xref>c, along with a HRTEM image of a single Ag&#x2013;Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterotrimer in <xref rid="fig1">Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig1">1</xref></xref>e. The observed lattice spacings are 2.3, 2.0, and 4.9 &#xc5;, which are consistent with the (111) plane of Ag, the (100) plane of Pt, and the (111) plane of Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub>, respectively. The STEM-EDS element mapping data in <xref rid="fig1">Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig1">1</xref></xref>d further confirms the formation of an Ag&#x2013;Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterotrimer, based on comparing the spatial distribution of the Ag L-shell, Pt M-shell, and Fe K-shell transitions with the corresponding STEM image in the inset.</p><fig fig-type="figure" id="fig1" position="float"><label>Figure 1</label><caption><p>(a) TEM image of Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterodimer seeds and (b) STEM-EDS line scan of a typical Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterodimer, showing the distribution of Fe and Pt across the hybrid particle. (c) Representative TEM image of Ag&#x2013;Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterotrimers, which form from the nucleation of Ag on the Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterodimers shown in (a). (d) Composite STEM-EDS element map of an individual Ag&#x2013;Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterotrimer particle (corresponding STEM image shown in the inset) that includes an overlay of the Ag L-shell (yellow), Pt M-shell (blue), and Fe K-shell (red) transitions. (e) HRTEM image of a representative Ag&#x2013;Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterotrimer, highlighting lattice spacings that are characteristic of Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub>, Pt, and Ag.</p></caption><graphic id="gr1" position="float" xlink:href="nn-2013-05943z_0001.tif"/></fig><p>Taken together, these data confirm that the Pt domains of as-synthesized Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterodimers are active and selective toward nucleation of Ag to form exclusively Ag&#x2013;Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterotrimers. However, in order to access other isomers, the reactivity of the Pt domain must be blocked so that only the Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> surface is exposed and capable of nucleating Ag. Under identical reaction conditions, Ag is known to nucleate on both Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> and Pt nanoparticle surfaces when the Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> and Pt nanoparticles are isolated from one another, <italic>e</italic>.<italic>g</italic>., when they are <underline>not</underline> connected as hybrid nanoparticles, and this capability helped to motivate our choice of Ag/Pt/Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> as a model system for proof-of-concept studies.<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref21">(21)</xref> Ag therefore also has an affinity for the Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> surface, which suggests that if the Pt surface is blocked and only the Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> surface is accessible, Ag may nucleate on Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> instead of Pt to produce a distinct isomer, Ag&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub>&#x2013;Pt. Chemistry similar to that used to synthesize the Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterodimers&#xe5f8;reaction of Au seeds with Fe(CO)<sub>5</sub> in 1-octadecene&#xe5f8;has been used to make Au&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterodimers with a thin iron oxide shell surrounding the Au domain.<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref28">(28)</xref> This suggests that it may be possible to install a thin iron oxide shell on the Pt surface of the Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterodimers in order to block access to Pt and instead direct nucleation of Ag onto the Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> surface.</p><p>We found that a key and highly reproducible experimental variable for coating the Pt domain with an iron oxide shell is through careful adjustment of the molar ratio of oleic acid to Fe(CO)<sub>5</sub>. Specifically, when the molar ratio of oleic acid to Fe(CO)<sub>5</sub> is reduced from the typical value of 3:1<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref28">(28)</xref> to 1.5:1, the resulting Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterodimers exhibit a thin oxide shell on the Pt domain. A representative TEM image (<xref rid="fig2">Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig2">2</xref></xref>a) shows Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterodimers that, at low magnification, look identical to those shown in <xref rid="fig1">Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig1">1</xref></xref>a. However, a higher-magnification image (<xref rid="fig2">Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig2">2</xref></xref>b) reveals that there are shells around the Pt domains, and this is confirmed by the HRTEM image in <xref rid="fig2">Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig2">2</xref></xref>c. The HRTEM image in <xref rid="fig2">Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig2">2</xref></xref>c also indicates that the iron oxide shell that surrounds the Pt domain is amorphous. A STEM-EDS line scan (<xref rid="fig2">Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig2">2</xref></xref>d) shows the distribution of Pt and Fe across a corresponding Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterodimer. In comparison with the STEM-EDS line scan in <xref rid="fig1">Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig1">1</xref></xref>b for the Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterodimer with no shell, where the Fe signal approaches baseline toward the edge of the Pt domain, the Fe signal persists across the Pt domain, including at its edge. This is consistent with the presence of an iron oxide shell surrounding the Pt domain. Further support of an iron oxide shell is provided by the HAADF-STEM images in <xref rid="fig3">Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig3">3</xref></xref>, which clearly show that shells of similar Z-contrast to those of the Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> regions surround the Pt particles in Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterodimers that were prepared with a 1.5:1 ratio of oleic acid to Fe(CO)<sub>5</sub>. For comparison, no such shell is observed in the HAADF-STEM images of the Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterodimers prepared using the traditional 3:1 ratio of oleic acid to Fe(CO)<sub>5</sub>. Collectively, the data indicate that decreasing the oleic acid concentration relative to that of Fe(CO)<sub>5</sub> leads to the growth of an iron oxide shell that coats the surface of the Pt domain.</p><fig fig-type="figure" id="fig2" position="float"><label>Figure 2</label><caption><p>(a, b) Representative TEM images, at two different magnifications, of Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterodimers that contain an amorphous iron oxide shell surrounding the Pt domain. (c) HRTEM image of a single Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterodimer containing an iron oxide shell, showing that the Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> domain is crystalline and the shell surrounding the Pt domain is amorphous. (d) STEM-EDS line scan of a Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterodimer containing an iron oxide shell, showing the distribution of Fe and Pt across the particle.</p></caption><graphic id="gr2" position="float" xlink:href="nn-2013-05943z_0002.tif"/></fig><fig fig-type="figure" id="fig3" position="float"><label>Figure 3</label><caption><p>HAADF STEM images of (left) Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterodimers and (right) Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterodimers that contain an iron oxide shell surrounding the Pt domain. All scale bars are 5 nm.</p></caption><graphic id="gr3" position="float" xlink:href="nn-2013-05943z_0003.tif"/></fig><p>While the reaction of the Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterodimers from <xref rid="fig1">Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig1">1</xref></xref>a with Ag(C<sub>2</sub>H<sub>3</sub>O<sub>2</sub>) in toluene at 60 &#xb0;C led exclusively to the formation of Ag&#x2013;Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterotrimers (<xref rid="fig1">Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig1">1</xref></xref>c), the reaction under the same conditions but instead using the Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterodimers from <xref rid="fig2">Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig2">2</xref></xref>&#xe5f8;which contain a thin iron oxide shell surrounding the Pt domain&#xe5f8;does <underline>not</underline> result in nucleation of Ag on Pt, but rather exclusively on Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub>. <xref rid="fig4">Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig4">4</xref></xref>a shows a representative TEM image of the Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub>&#x2013;Ag heterotrimers. <xref rid="fig4">Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig4">4</xref></xref>b&#x2013;f show STEM-EDS element mapping data that confirm the spatial distribution of Ag, Pt, and Fe in a representative Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub>&#x2013;Ag heterotrimer. Closer inspection of the TEM image in <xref rid="fig4">Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig4">4</xref></xref>a reveals that 85% of the sample consists of heterotrimer products with three distinct morphologies, and 15% of the sample consists of non-heterotrimer impurities (<italic>e</italic>.<italic>g</italic>., Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub>, Pt, Ag). Linear and bent Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub>&#x2013;Ag morphologies account for 15% and 47% of the heterotrimer portion of the product, respectively. Interestingly, the remaining 38% of the heterotrimers appear, at first glance, to consist of Ag&#x2013;Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> linkages, with Ag nucleating on the Pt surface. However, HRTEM images, shown and discussed below, confirm that all of the Ag does indeed nucleate on iron oxide, not on Pt.</p><fig fig-type="figure" id="fig4" position="float"><label>Figure 4</label><caption><p>(a) Representative TEM image of Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub>&#x2013;Ag heterotrimers. (b) STEM image and corresponding element maps for the (c) Fe K-shell, (d) Ag L-shell, and (e) Pt M-shell transitions. A composite STEM-EDS element map, including an overlay of the Ag (yellow), Pt (blue), and Fe (red) element maps from (c)&#x2013;(e), is shown in (f). The Pt domain appears purple in the composite image in (f) because the Pt is covered by a shell of iron oxide and therefore the Pt (blue) and Fe (red) signals overlap.</p></caption><graphic id="gr4" position="float" xlink:href="nn-2013-05943z_0004.tif"/></fig><p><xref rid="fig5">Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig5">5</xref></xref> shows representative HRTEM images for the three types of Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub>&#x2013;Ag heterotrimers that were observed in <xref rid="fig4">Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig4">4</xref></xref>. The linear Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub>&#x2013;Ag heterotrimer exhibits lattice spacings of 2.4, 2.3, and 4.9 &#xc5;, which correspond to the (111) plane of Ag, the (111) plane of Pt, and the (111) plane of Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub>, respectively. The bent Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub>&#x2013;Ag heterotrimer shows lattice spacings of 2.0, 1.9, and 2.5 &#xc5;, which are consistent with the (100) plane of Ag, the (100) plane of Pt, and the (311) plane of Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub>, respectively. The third heterotrimer morphology exhibits lattice spacings of 2.3, 2.3, and 2.9 &#xc5;, which correspond to the (111) plane of Ag, the (111) plane of Pt, and the (121) plane of Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub>, respectively. At low magnification, this third heterotrimer morphology appears to include the conventional Ag&#x2013;Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> linkage, but the HRTEM image in <xref rid="fig5">Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig5">5</xref></xref>c reveals that it actually contains a thin amorphous region separating the Pt and Ag domains. This is consistent with the presence of the protective iron oxide shell that was formed during the heterodimer synthesis (see <xref rid="fig2">Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig2">2</xref></xref>b,c), and it indicates that Ag can nucleate on both the Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> domain and on the protective shell, since both consist of iron oxide. Therefore, none of the three heterotrimer morphologies formed using the protected Pt domain contain a Pt&#x2013;Ag interface, which fully distinguishes them from the Ag&#x2013;Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> configuration that contains exclusively Pt&#x2013;Ag (and not Ag&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub>) interfaces.</p><fig fig-type="figure" id="fig5" position="float"><label>Figure 5</label><caption><p>HRTEM images of the three distinct Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub>&#x2013;Ag heterotrimer morphologies that were observed: (a) bent Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub>&#x2013;Ag geometry, (b) linear Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub>&#x2013;Ag geometry, and (c) linear Ag-(FeO<sub><italic>x</italic></sub>)&#x2013;Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> geometry. In (c), note the region between the crystalline Ag and Pt domains, which corresponds to the amorphous iron oxide shell that surrounds the Pt domain. All three HRTEM images include lattice spacings that are characteristic of Ag, Pt, and Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub>.</p></caption><graphic id="gr5" position="float" xlink:href="nn-2013-05943z_0005.tif"/></fig><p>Different domain configurations are expected to result in different properties. For reasons outlined previously, Ag&#x2013;Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> and Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub>&#x2013;Ag were chosen as model systems for demonstrating the concept of using solid-state protection to direct site-specific nucleation, for accessing multiple distinct ternary nanoparticle isomers, and for understanding how the nanoparticle protecting group chemistry can be reproducibly applied. However, Ag&#x2013;Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> and Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub>&#x2013;Ag contain functional domains, including plasmonic Ag nanoparticles, so it is possible to validate that different properties arise from the different configurations. Accordingly, <xref rid="notes-1">Figure S1</xref> shows UV&#x2013;visible absorption spectra for Ag&#x2013;Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> and Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub>&#x2013;Ag heterotrimers in hexanes. The Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub>&#x2013;Ag sample has a single absorption peak with &#x3bb;<sub>max</sub> = 402 nm, which is consistent with the peak at 400 nm observed for Ag nanoparticles of similar size in hexanes.<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref30">(30)</xref> These results are also consistent with previous studies, which have shown that there is no substantial shift in the plasmon frequency of Ag when it is bound to Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub>, indicating weak interaction between these domains.<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref31">(31)</xref> In contrast, the Ag&#x2013;Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> sample exhibited a single peak at 432 nm, which represents a 30 nm red shift compared to the Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub>&#x2013;Ag isomer and the typical absorption peak for free Ag nanoparticles. The shift in the Ag surface plasmon resonance is likely a result of interaction with the bound Pt domain and is consistent with previous reports describing similar systems. For example, Ag nanoparticles coated with a discontinuous Pt shell were found to exhibit a 37 nm red shift from the characteristic plasmonic absorption of Ag nanoparticles (400 nm), which was attributed to the presence of the Pt domain.<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref32">(32)</xref></p></sec><sec id="sec2.2"><title>Nucleation of Au on Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> Heterodimers</title><p>To further interrogate the ability of the thin iron oxide shell to prevent the Pt domain from serving as a nucleation site for additional metal nanoparticles, we studied the nucleation of Au onto Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterodimers, both with and without an iron oxide shell covering the Pt. Under the conditions used in these experiments&#xe5f8;appropriate soluble metal salts, Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterodimers in nonpolar solvents, and a reaction temperature of 60 &#xb0;C&#xe5f8;it is known that Ag nucleates on both Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> and Pt nanoparticles when they are separate from one another, but Au only nucleates on Pt and <underline>not</underline> on Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub>. Therefore, upon reaction of the Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterodimers from <xref rid="fig1">Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig1">1</xref></xref>a with HAuCl<sub>4</sub>, Au&#x2013;Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> was the expected product.<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref21">(21)</xref> Consistent with this, exclusive formation of the Au&#x2013;Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterotrimer was indeed observed. Representative TEM and HRTEM images of these Au&#x2013;Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterotrimers are shown in <xref rid="fig6">Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig6">6</xref></xref>b and c, and the observed lattice spacings of 2.0, 1.9, and 2.9 &#xc5; are consistent with the (200), (100), and (121) planes of Au, Pt, and Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub>, respectively.</p><fig fig-type="figure" id="fig6" position="float"><label>Figure 6</label><caption><p>(a) Schematic highlighting the nucleation of Au on Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterodimers (without an iron oxide shell) to form the Au&#x2013;Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterotrimer and (b) the corresponding TEM image, along with (c) an HRTEM image of a representative Au&#x2013;Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterotrimer. (d) Schematic highlighting the inability of the protected Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterodimer to nucleate Au and (e) the corresponding TEM image showing free Au particles along with Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub>, as well as (f) a representative HRTEM image showing an unbound Au nanoparticle next to a Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterodimer. All HRTEM images exhibit lattice spacings that are characteristic of Au, Pt, and Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub>.</p></caption><graphic id="gr6" position="float" xlink:href="nn-2013-05943z_0006.tif"/></fig><p>In contrast, for the Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterodimers having the Pt domain protected by a thin iron oxide shell, only iron oxide is exposed, and thus the entire surface should be unreactive toward nucleation of Au. Consistent with this, when the protected Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterodimers from <xref rid="fig2">Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig2">2</xref></xref> were reacted with HAuCl<sub>4</sub>&#xb7;3H<sub>2</sub>O in ODE at 60 &#xb0;C, we saw no evidence of Au growing on Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub>. Representative TEM images (<xref rid="fig6">Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig6">6</xref></xref>e) show unaltered Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterodimers and free Au particles, indicating that Au nucleated independently of the Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterodimers. The corresponding HRTEM image (<xref rid="fig6">Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig6">6</xref></xref>f) shows a lattice spacing of 2.4 &#xc5; on a representative free particle, and this is consistent with the (111) plane of Au and lattice spacings in the heterodimer particles of 1.9 and 4.8 &#xc5;, which are consistent with the (100) and (111) planes of Pt and Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub>, respectively.</p></sec><sec id="sec2.3"><title>Understanding and Controlling the Formation of the Iron Oxide Shell</title><p>The iron oxide shell that covers the Pt domain of Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterodimers serves as a solid-state analogue of a molecular projecting group, since it prevents Ag and Au from nucleating on the Pt surface, which otherwise would be the most favorable site. Because of the critical role that the iron oxide shell plays in directing the nucleation of the third nanoparticle domain, and therefore in the selective formation of two distinct ternary nanoparticle isomers, it is important to understand how it forms and how it can be controlled. To achieve such understanding, we systematically varied the amount of oleic acid used to synthesize the Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterodimers while keeping the concentrations of Fe(CO)<sub>5</sub> and the Pt seeds constant. As mentioned previously, the iron oxide shell coating the Pt domain emerges when the molar ratio of oleic acid to Fe(CO)<sub>5</sub> is decreased to 1.5:1 from the standard literature value of 3:1,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref29">(29)</xref> and therefore oleic acid concentration was identified as the key variable that determines whether or not a protective iron oxide shell forms.</p><p>The standard 3:1 molar ratio of oleic acid to Fe(CO)<sub>5</sub> is the precise quantity required to form the iron oleate complex Fe(C<sub>18</sub>H<sub>33</sub>O<sub>2</sub>)<sub>3</sub>, which is the most likely <italic>in situ</italic> precursor that leads to the formation of the Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> domain. Indeed, when a 3:1 ratio of oleic acid to Fe(CO)<sub>5</sub> was used in the synthesis of Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub>, the heterodimers showed no visual evidence of an iron oxide shell coating the Pt domain (<xref rid="fig7">Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig7">7</xref></xref>a), and as discussed previously, the Pt domain was clearly exposed because both Au and Ag nucleated on it to form M&#x2013;Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterotrimers (M = Au, Ag). When the molar ratio of oleic acid to Fe(CO)<sub>5</sub> was decreased to 1.5:1&#xe5f8;the value used in the preceding sections to protect the Pt domain&#xe5f8;the predominant morphology consisted of Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterodimers with a thin iron oxide shell surrounding the Pt domain (<xref rid="fig7">Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig7">7</xref></xref>b). When the molar ratio was decreased further to 0.6:1, an asymmetric core&#x2013;shell morphology was observed that is best described as a combination of core&#x2013;shell and heterodimer morphologies (<xref rid="fig7">Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig7">7</xref></xref>c). Finally, when no oleic acid was added to the reaction, the predominant morphology consisted of Pt/iron oxide core/shell and free iron oxide nanoparticles (<xref rid="fig7">Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig7">7</xref></xref>d).</p><fig fig-type="figure" id="fig7" position="float"><label>Figure 7</label><caption><p>Representative TEM images of iron oxide/platinum nanoparticles formed by varying the ratio of oleic acid to Fe(CO)<sub>5</sub> during their synthesis, as indicated: (a) a 3:1 ratio forms Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterodimers, (b) a 1.5:1 ratio forms Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterodimers that have a thin iron oxide shell surrounding the Pt domain, (c) a 0.6:1 ratio forms asymmetric nanostructures that are intermediate between Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterodimers and Pt/Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> core/shell nanoparticles, and (d) no oleic acid forms Pt/Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> core/shell nanoparticles.</p></caption><graphic id="gr7" position="float" xlink:href="nn-2013-05943z_0007.tif"/></fig><p>The impact that the molar ratio of oleic acid to Fe(CO)<sub>5</sub> has on the morphology of the Pt/Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> nanostructures is clearly visible by comparing the TEM images in <xref rid="fig7">Figure <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig7">7</xref></xref>: as the amount of oleic acid is increased, the morphology can be systematically tuned from a core&#x2013;shell structure to a heterodimer, and distinct intermediates can be isolated. These observations suggest that there are two competing pathways: one that results in a core&#x2013;shell structure and one that results in heterodimers. When no oleic acid is present, Fe(CO)<sub>5</sub> is the only source of iron, and no iron oleate can form. Fe(CO)<sub>5</sub> is known to thermally decompose in solution to form Fe or Fe alloy nanoparticles,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref33">(33)</xref> while iron oleate is known to thermally decompose in solution to form iron oxide nanoparticles.<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref34">(34)</xref> We therefore suggest that when only Fe(CO)<sub>5</sub> is present, it thermally decomposes in solution to form Fe<sup>0</sup>, which deposits onto the surface of the Pt seed particles and oxidizes during workup in air to form a Pt@FeO<sub><italic>x</italic></sub> core&#x2013;shell morphology. In contrast, when sufficient oleic acid is present to react with all of the Fe(CO)<sub>5</sub>, <italic>e</italic>.<italic>g</italic>., at molar ratios &#x2265;3:1, all of the iron in solution exists as iron oleate, which decomposes to produce the Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> domain of the Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterodimers. At intermediate ratios of oleic acid to Fe(CO)<sub>5</sub>, where oleic acid is the limiting reagent, some of the iron in solution is present as iron oleate, while the rest remains as Fe(CO)<sub>5</sub>. Therefore, the two competing thermal decomposition reactions can occur simultaneously, and the amount of iron incorporated into the iron oxide shell and the Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> domain is determined by the <italic>in situ</italic> concentration of Fe(CO)<sub>5</sub> and iron oleate, respectively. These insights lead to a highly reproducible route for installing the iron oxide protecting group onto the Pt domain.</p></sec></sec><sec id="sec3"><title>Conclusions</title><p>A fundamental challenge in the synthesis of high-order hybrid nanoparticles&#xe5f8;one that underpins the construction of functional nanoarchitectures for applications that include solar energy conversion and optics&#xe5f8;is the controlled placement of one nanoparticle relative to others. Such control is necessary to ensure that the spatial arrangements, domain configurations, and proper materials linkages and interfaces required for a target function can be realized experimentally and in high yield. As an important step toward this goal, we have introduced a solid-state analogue of molecular protecting group chemistry to direct the nucleation of a nanoparticle selectively onto one domain of a colloidal heterodimer <italic>vs</italic> another, effectively rendering the preferred nucleation site inaccessible so that an otherwise disfavored ternary configuration is accessible.</p><p>Specifically, we demonstrated that a thin shell of amorphous iron oxide can be installed onto the Pt domain of Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterodimers. Nucleation of Ag onto Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> typically results in the exclusive formation of Ag&#x2013;Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterotrimers. However, nucleation of Ag onto Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterodimers that have the Pt domain protected with a thin iron oxide shell instead occurs exclusively on the exposed iron oxide surface, <italic>not</italic> on the Pt. This results in the formation of the otherwise disfavored heterotrimer Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub>&#x2013;Ag, which has a different configuration with distinct materials linkages and also different optical properties than the favored Ag&#x2013;Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterotrimer. Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub>&#x2013;Ag and Ag&#x2013;Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> can be considered as isomers, since they contain the same nanoparticles in different configurations, and therefore the nanoparticle protecting group chemistry provides a predictable pathway to distinct ternary nanoparticle isomers. Such ternary colloidal nanoparticle isomers represent an important step toward controlling the high-order configurations and materials linkages that underpin many emerging applications of colloidal hybrid nanoparticles. Systematic studies revealed that the ratio of oleic acid to Fe(CO)<sub>5</sub> used during the synthesis of the Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterodimers is the key variable that controls whether or not a protective iron oxide shell is installed on the Pt domain. These same systematic studies also provided new insights into how one can tune between core&#x2013;shell and heterodimer morphologies within the same materials system.</p><p>This protecting group chemistry represents an important addition to the growing &#x201c;total synthesis&#x201d; toolbox for rationally constructing high-order hybrid nanoparticles.<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref21 ref27">(21, 27)</xref> As a model proof-of-concept system, installing an amorphous iron oxide shell onto the Pt domain of Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterodimers and using it to direct the subsequent nucleation of Ag and Au nanoparticles into otherwise disfavored configurations serves as an initial demonstration of the concept of colloidal nanoparticle protecting group chemistry. However, such protecting group capabilities must be expanded to other materials systems, be made more selective with respect to subsequent nucleation, and be capable of being removed to re-expose the protected domain. Research along these lines is currently under way. Preliminary evidence suggests that the amorphous iron oxide shell can be removed; thus deprotection is indeed likely to be achievable in this system.</p></sec><sec id="sec4"><title>Materials and Methods</title><sec id="sec4.1"><title>Materials</title><p>1-Octadecene [ODE, technical grade, 90%], oleic acid [OLAC, technical grade, 90%], platinum(II) acetylacetonate [Pt(acac)<sub>2</sub>, 97%], iron(0) pentacarbonyl [Fe(CO)<sub>5</sub>, &gt;99.99%], and gold(III) chloride hydrate [HAuCl<sub>4</sub>&#xb7;3H<sub>2</sub>O] were purchased from Sigma-Aldrich. Silver(I) acetate [Ag(C<sub>2</sub>H<sub>3</sub>O<sub>2</sub>), anhydrous] was purchased from Alfa Aesar. Oleylamine [OLAM, C<sub>18</sub> content 80&#x2013;90%] was purchased from Acros Organics. Solvents, including hexanes, toluene, isopropyl alcohol [IPA], and ethanol [EtOH], were of analytical grade. All chemicals were used as received.</p></sec><sec id="sec4.2"><title>Synthesis of 4 nm Pt Nanoparticles</title><p>Using a modification of a published procedure,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref28">(28)</xref> Pt(acac)<sub>2</sub> (200 mg) was added to a mixture of 1-octadecene (20 mL), oleylamine (2 mL), and oleic acid (2 mL) in a 100 mL three-neck flask. The solution was heated to 120 &#xb0;C under vacuum, then heated to 185 &#xb0;C under a blanket of Ar, at which point 0.2 mL of an Fe(CO)<sub>5</sub> solution [0.1 mL of Fe(CO)<sub>5</sub> in 1 mL of hexanes] was swiftly injected. The reaction was then heated to 190 &#xb0;C and left for 1 h. After cooling to room temperature, the particles were precipitated from solution using IPA, followed by centrifugation. The particles were redispersed in hexanes, and the process was repeated using EtOH. The resulting product was suspended in 4 mL of hexanes solution that contained 1% oleylamine and 1% oleic acid.</p></sec><sec id="sec4.3"><title>Synthesis of Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> Heterodimers</title><p>Using a modification of a published procedure,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="ref28">(28)</xref> 1-octadecene (10 mL) and oleic acid (0.6 mL) were placed into a 100 mL three-neck flask equipped with a reflux condenser, and the solution was degassed at 120 &#xb0;C for 30 min under a flow of Ar. The reaction was then placed under an Ar blanket, and Fe(CO)<sub>5</sub> [0.07 mL dispersed in 0.25 mL of ODE] was injected. After 5 min, oleylamine (0.5 mL) and then Pt seeds [10 mg in 1 mL of hexanes dispersion] were injected. The reaction was heated to 310 &#xb0;C and left for 30 min. After cooling to room temperature, the particles were precipitated from the cooled solution using IPA, followed by centrifugation. The particles were then redispersed in hexanes, and the process was repeated using EtOH. The resulting product was suspended in 4 mL of hexanes solution that contained 1% oleic acid and 1% oleylamine.</p></sec><sec id="sec4.4"><title>Synthesis of Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> Heterodimers with an Iron Oxide Shell</title><p>Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterodimers with an iron oxide shell on the Pt domain were synthesized using the same procedure described above except that the volume of oleic acid was decreased to 0.25 mL. The volume of oleic acid was further decreased to 0.1 and 0 mL to increase the thickness of the shell.</p></sec><sec id="sec4.5"><title>Synthesis of Ag&#x2013;Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> and Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub>&#x2013;Ag Heterotrimer Isomers</title><p>Ag(C<sub>2</sub>H<sub>3</sub>O<sub>2</sub>) (12.5 mg) was dissolved in toluene (10 mL) that contained oleylamine (0.75 mL), followed by the addition of Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterodimers (10 mg in 1 mL of hexanes suspension) with or without a shell, depending on which heterotrimer isomer was desired. The solution was heated to 60 &#xb0;C under an Ar blanket and left for 14 h. After cooling to room temperature, the product was precipitated using EtOH and centrifuged for 3 min at 9000 rpm. The resulting product was suspended in 4 mL of hexanes solution that contained 1% oleic acid and 1% oleylamine.</p></sec><sec id="sec4.6"><title>Au/Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> Control Experiment</title><p>HAuCl<sub>4</sub>&#xb7;H<sub>2</sub>O (25 mg) was dissolved in 1-octadecene (5 mL) and oleylamine (0.75 mL) in a 50 mL flask, and the solution was heated to 60 &#xb0;C, at which point Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> heterodimers (10 mg in 1 mL of hexanes) were injected. The temperature was held at 60 &#xb0;C for 4 h. After cooling to room temperature, the particles were precipitated with IPA, followed by centrifugation. The resulting product was suspended in 4 mL of hexanes solution that contained 1% oleic acid and 1% oleylamine.</p></sec><sec id="sec4.7"><title>Characterization</title><p>Transmission electron microscopy (TEM) images were obtained using a JEOL 1200 EX II operating at 80 kV. High-resolution TEM (HRTEM), high angle annular dark-field scanning transmission electron microscopy (HAADF-STEM), and STEM energy-dispersive spectroscopy (STEM-EDS) analyses were obtained using a JEOL 2010F field emission microscope operating at 200 kV and equipped with an EDAX solid-state X-ray detector. ES Vision software (Emispec) was used for EDS data analyses. Particle distributions were determined using ImageJ software. Samples for TEM and STEM-EDS were prepared by drop-casting nanoparticles dispersed in hexanes onto Formvar-coated Cu grids. Lattice spacings were determined using HRTEM images and ImageJ software. UV&#x2013;visible absorption spectra were acquired on nanoparticles dispersed in hexanes using an Ocean Optics HR400 spectrometer equipped with a DH-2000-BAL light source.</p></sec></sec></body><back><ack><title>Acknowledgment</title><p>This work was supported by the U.S. National Science Foundation under grant CHE-1213475. TEM imaging was performed in the Penn State Microscopy and Cytometry Facility (University Park, PA, USA), and HRTEM imaging was performed at the Materials Characterization Lab of the Penn State Materials Research Institute.</p></ack><notes id="notes-1" notes-type="si">
<title><inline-supplementary-material xlink:href="/doi/suppl/10.1021/nn405943z">Supporting Information</inline-supplementary-material></title><p>UV&#x2013;visible absorption spectra for Ag&#x2013;Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> and Pt&#x2013;Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub>&#x2013;Ag heterotrimers. This material is available free of charge <italic>via</italic> the Internet at <uri xlink:href="http://pubs.acs.org">http://pubs.acs.org</uri>.</p></notes><notes notes-type="conflict-of-interest"><p>The authors declare no competing financial interest.</p></notes><ref-list><title>References</title><ref id="ref1"><label>1. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit1"><name><surname>Carbone</surname><x>, </x><given-names>L.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Cozzoli</surname><x>, </x><given-names>P. D.</given-names></name><article-title>Colloidal Heterostructured Nanocrystals: Synthesis and Growth Mechanisms</article-title><source>Nano Today</source><x> </x><year>2010</year><x>, </x><volume>5</volume><x>, </x><fpage>449</fpage><x>&ndash;</x><lpage>493</lpage></citation></ref><ref id="ref2"><label>2. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit2"><name><surname>Costi</surname><x>, </x><given-names>R.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Saunders</surname><x>, </x><given-names>A. E.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Banin</surname><x>, </x><given-names>U.</given-names></name><article-title>Colloidal Hybrid Nanostructures: A New Type of Functional Materials</article-title><source>Angew. Chem., Int. Ed.</source><x> </x><year>2010</year><x>, </x><volume>49</volume><x>, </x><fpage>4878</fpage><x>&ndash;</x><lpage>4897</lpage></citation></ref><ref id="ref3"><label>3. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit3"><name><surname>Cozzoli</surname><x>, </x><given-names>P. D.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Pellegrino</surname><x>, </x><given-names>T.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Manna</surname><x>, </x><given-names>L.</given-names></name><article-title>Synthesis, Properties and Perspectives of Hybrid Nanocrystal Structures</article-title><source>Chem. Soc. Rev.</source><x> </x><year>2006</year><x>, </x><volume>35</volume><x>, </x><fpage>1195</fpage><x>&ndash;</x><lpage>1208</lpage></citation></ref><ref id="ref4"><label>4. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit4"><name><surname>Wang</surname><x>, </x><given-names>C.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Xu</surname><x>, </x><given-names>C.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Zeng</surname><x>, </x><given-names>H.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Sun</surname><x>, </x><given-names>S.</given-names></name><article-title>Recent Progress in Synthesis and Applications of Dumbbell-Like Nanoparticles</article-title><source>Adv. Mater.</source><x> </x><year>2009</year><x>, </x><volume>21</volume><x>, </x><fpage>3045</fpage><x>&ndash;</x><lpage>3052</lpage></citation></ref><ref id="ref5"><label>5. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit5"><name><surname>Casavola</surname><x>, </x><given-names>M.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Buonsanti</surname><x>, </x><given-names>R.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Caputo</surname><x>, </x><given-names>G.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Cozzoli</surname><x>, </x><given-names>P. D.</given-names></name><article-title>Colloidal Strategies for Preparing Oxide-Based Hybrid Nanocrystals</article-title><source>Eur. J. Inorg. Chem.</source><x> </x><year>2008</year><x>, </x><volume>6</volume><x>, </x><fpage>837</fpage><x>&ndash;</x><lpage>854</lpage></citation></ref><ref id="ref6"><label>6. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit6"><name><surname>Mieszawska</surname><x>, </x><given-names>A. J.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Jalilian</surname><x>, </x><given-names>R.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Sumanasekera</surname><x>, </x><given-names>G. U.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Zamborini</surname><x>, </x><given-names>F. P.</given-names></name><article-title>The Synthesis and Fabrication of One-Dimensional Nanoscale Heterojunctions</article-title><source>Small</source><x> </x><year>2007</year><x>, </x><volume>3</volume><x>, </x><fpage>722</fpage><x>&ndash;</x><lpage>756</lpage></citation></ref><ref id="ref7"><label>7. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit7"><name><surname>Hu</surname><x>, </x><given-names>J.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Bando</surname><x>, </x><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Golberg</surname><x>, </x><given-names>D.</given-names></name><article-title>Novel Semiconducting Nanowire Heterostructures: Synthesis, Properties and Applications</article-title><source>J. Mater. Chem.</source><x> </x><year>2009</year><x>, </x><volume>19</volume><x>, </x><fpage>330</fpage><x>&ndash;</x><lpage>343</lpage></citation></ref><ref id="ref8"><label>8. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit8"><name><surname>Feng</surname><x>, </x><given-names>X.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Hu</surname><x>, </x><given-names>G.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Hu</surname><x>, </x><given-names>J.</given-names></name><article-title>Solution-Phase Synthesis of Metal and/or Semiconductor Homojunction/Heterojunction Nanomaterials</article-title><source>Nanoscale</source><x> </x><year>2011</year><x>, </x><volume>3</volume><x>, </x><fpage>2099</fpage><x>&ndash;</x><lpage>2117</lpage></citation></ref><ref id="ref9"><label>9. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit9"><name><surname>Chaundhuri</surname><x>, </x><given-names>R. G.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Paria</surname><x>, </x><given-names>S.</given-names></name><article-title>Core/Shell Nanoparticles: Classes, Properties, Synthesis Mechanisms, Characterization, and Applications</article-title><source>Chem. Rev.</source><x> </x><year>2012</year><x>, </x><volume>112</volume><x>, </x><fpage>2373</fpage><x>&ndash;</x><lpage>2433</lpage></citation></ref><ref id="ref10"><label>10. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit10"><name><surname>Amirav</surname><x>, </x><given-names>L.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Alivisatos</surname><x>, </x><given-names>A. P.</given-names></name><article-title>Photocatalytic Hydrogen Production with Tunable Nanorod Heterostructures</article-title><source>J. Phys. Chem. Lett.</source><x> </x><year>2010</year><x>, </x><volume>1</volume><x>, </x><fpage>1051</fpage><x>&ndash;</x><lpage>1054</lpage></citation></ref><ref id="ref11"><label>11. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit11a"><label>a</label><name><surname>Elmalem</surname><x>, </x><given-names>E.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Saunders</surname><x>, </x><given-names>A. E.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Costi</surname><x>, </x><given-names>R.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Salant</surname><x>, </x><given-names>A.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Banin</surname><x>, </x><given-names>U.</given-names></name><article-title>Growth of Photocatalytic CdSe-Pt Nanorods and Nanonets</article-title><source>Adv. Mater.</source><x> </x><year>2008</year><x>, </x><volume>20</volume><x>, </x><fpage>4312</fpage><x>&ndash;</x><lpage>4317</lpage></citation><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit11b"><label>b</label><name><surname>Habas</surname><x>, </x><given-names>S. E.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Yang</surname><x>, </x><given-names>P.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Mokari</surname><x>, </x><given-names>T.</given-names></name><article-title>Selective Growth of Metal and Binary Metal Tips on CdS Nanorods</article-title><source>J. Am. Chem. Soc.</source><x> </x><year>2008</year><x>, </x><volume>130</volume><x>, </x><fpage>3294</fpage><x>&ndash;</x><lpage>3295</lpage></citation></ref><ref id="ref12"><label>12. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit12"><name><surname>Costi</surname><x>, </x><given-names>R.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Saunders</surname><x>, </x><given-names>A. E.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Elmalem</surname><x>, </x><given-names>E.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Salant</surname><x>, </x><given-names>A.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Banin</surname><x>, </x><given-names>U.</given-names></name><article-title>Visible Light-Induced Charge Retention and Photocatalysis with Hybrid CdSe-Au Nanodumbbells</article-title><source>Nano Lett.</source><x> </x><year>2008</year><x>, </x><volume>8</volume><x>, </x><fpage>637</fpage><x>&ndash;</x><lpage>641</lpage></citation></ref><ref id="ref13"><label>13. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit13"><name><surname>Bang</surname><x>, </x><given-names>J. H.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Kamat</surname><x>, </x><given-names>P.</given-names></name><article-title>Quantum Dot Sensitized Solar Cells. A Tale of Two Semiconductor Nanocrystals: CdSe and CdTe</article-title><source>ACS Nano</source><x> </x><year>2009</year><x>, </x><volume>3</volume><x>, </x><fpage>1467</fpage><x>&ndash;</x><lpage>1476</lpage></citation></ref><ref id="ref14"><label>14. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit14"><name><surname>Yin</surname><x>, </x><given-names>H.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Wang</surname><x>, </x><given-names>C.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Zhu</surname><x>, </x><given-names>H.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Overbury</surname><x>, </x><given-names>S. H.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Sun</surname><x>, </x><given-names>S.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Dai</surname><x>, </x><given-names>S.</given-names></name><article-title>Colloidal Deposition Synthesis of Supported Gold Nanocatalysts based on Au-Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> Dumbbell Nanoparticles</article-title><source>Chem. Commun.</source><x> </x><year>2008</year><x>, </x><fpage>4357</fpage><x>&ndash;</x><lpage>4359</lpage></citation></ref><ref id="ref15"><label>15. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit15"><name><surname>Wang</surname><x>, </x><given-names>C.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Daimon</surname><x>, </x><given-names>H.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Sun</surname><x>, </x><given-names>S.</given-names></name><article-title>Dumbbell-Like Pt-Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> Nanoparticles and Their Enhanced Catalysis for Oxygen Reduction Reaction</article-title><source>Nano Lett.</source><x> </x><year>2009</year><x>, </x><volume>9</volume><x>, </x><fpage>1493</fpage><x>&ndash;</x><lpage>1496</lpage></citation></ref><ref id="ref16"><label>16. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit16"><name><surname>Figuerola</surname><x>, </x><given-names>A.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Fiore</surname><x>, </x><given-names>A.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Di Corata</surname><x>, </x><given-names>R.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Falqui</surname><x>, </x><given-names>A.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Giannini</surname><x>, </x><given-names>C.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Micotta</surname><x>, </x><given-names>E.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Lascialfari</surname><x>, </x><given-names>A.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Corti</surname><x>, </x><given-names>M.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Cingolani</surname><x>, </x><given-names>R.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Pellegrino</surname><x>, </x><given-names>T.</given-names></name><etal><italic>et</italic> <italic>al</italic>.</etal><article-title>One-Pot Synthesis and Characterization of Size-Controlled Bimagnetic FePt-Iron Oxide Heterodimer Crystals</article-title><source>J. Am. Chem. Soc.</source><x> </x><year>2008</year><x>, </x><volume>130</volume><x>, </x><fpage>1477</fpage><x>&ndash;</x><lpage>1487</lpage></citation></ref><ref id="ref17"><label>17. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit17"><name><surname>Mokari</surname><x>, </x><given-names>T.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Rothenberg</surname><x>, </x><given-names>E.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Popov</surname><x>, </x><given-names>I.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Costi</surname><x>, </x><given-names>R.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Banin</surname><x>, </x><given-names>U.</given-names></name><article-title>Selective Growth of Metal Tips onto Semiconductor Quantum Rods and Tetrapods</article-title><source>Science</source><x> </x><year>2004</year><x>, </x><volume>304</volume><x>, </x><fpage>1787</fpage><x>&ndash;</x><lpage>1790</lpage></citation></ref><ref id="ref18"><label>18. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit18"><name><surname>Xu</surname><x>, </x><given-names>C.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Xie</surname><x>, </x><given-names>J.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Ho</surname><x>, </x><given-names>D.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Wang</surname><x>, </x><given-names>C.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Kohler</surname><x>, </x><given-names>N.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Walsh</surname><x>, </x><given-names>E. G.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Morgan</surname><x>, </x><given-names>J. R.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Chin</surname><x>, </x><given-names>Y. E.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Sun</surname><x>, </x><given-names>S.</given-names></name><article-title>Au-Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> Dumbbell Nanoparticles as Dual-Functional Probes</article-title><source>Angew. Chem., Int. Ed.</source><x> </x><year>2008</year><x>, </x><volume>47</volume><x>, </x><fpage>173</fpage><x>&ndash;</x><lpage>176</lpage></citation></ref><ref id="ref19"><label>19. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit19"><name><surname>Bradley</surname><x>, </x><given-names>M. J.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Biacchi</surname><x>, </x><given-names>A. J.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Schaak</surname><x>, </x><given-names>R. E.</given-names></name><article-title>Chemical Transformation of Pt-Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> Colloidal Hybrid Nanoparticles into PtPb-Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> Heterodimers and (PtPb-Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub>)<sub>n</sub> Nanoflowers</article-title><source>Chem. Mater.</source><x> </x><year>2013</year><x>, </x><volume>25</volume><x>, </x><fpage>1886</fpage><x>&ndash;</x><lpage>1892</lpage></citation></ref><ref id="ref20"><label>20. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit20"><name><surname>Motl</surname><x>, </x><given-names>N. E.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Bondi</surname><x>, </x><given-names>J. F.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Schaak</surname><x>, </x><given-names>R. E.</given-names></name><article-title>Synthesis of Colloidal Au-Cu<sub>2</sub>S Heterodimers via Chemically Triggered Phase Segragation of AuCu Nanoparticles</article-title><source>Chem. Mater.</source><x> </x><year>2012</year><x>, </x><volume>24</volume><x>, </x><fpage>1552</fpage><x>&ndash;</x><lpage>1554</lpage></citation></ref><ref id="ref21"><label>21. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit21"><name><surname>Buck</surname><x>, </x><given-names>M. R.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Bondi</surname><x>, </x><given-names>J. F.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Schaak</surname><x>, </x><given-names>R. E.</given-names></name><article-title>A Total-Synthesis Framework for the Construction of High-Order Colloidal Hybrid Nanoparticles</article-title><source>Nat. Chem.</source><x> </x><year>2012</year><x>, </x><volume>4</volume><x>, </x><fpage>37</fpage><x>&ndash;</x><lpage>44</lpage></citation></ref><ref id="ref22"><label>22. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit22"><name><surname>Kamat</surname><x>, </x><given-names>P.</given-names></name><article-title>Manipulation of Charge Transfer Across Semiconductor Interface. A Criterion That Cannot Be Ignored in Photocatalyst Design</article-title><source>J. Phys. Chem. Lett.</source><x> </x><year>2012</year><x>, </x><volume>3</volume><x>, </x><fpage>663</fpage><x>&ndash;</x><lpage>672</lpage></citation></ref><ref id="ref23"><label>23. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit23"><name><surname>Fedutik</surname><x>, </x><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Temnov</surname><x>, </x><given-names>V.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Woggen</surname><x>, </x><given-names>U.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Ustinovich</surname><x>, </x><given-names>E.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Artemyev</surname><x>, </x><given-names>M.</given-names></name><article-title>Exciton-Plasmon Interaction in a Composite Metal-Insulator-Semiconductor Nanowire System</article-title><source>J. Am. Chem. Soc.</source><x> </x><year>2007</year><x>, </x><volume>129</volume><x>, </x><fpage>14939</fpage><x>&ndash;</x><lpage>14945</lpage></citation></ref><ref id="ref24"><label>24. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit24"><name><surname>Li</surname><x>, </x><given-names>Z.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Wang</surname><x>, </x><given-names>L.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Wang</surname><x>, </x><given-names>Z.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Liu</surname><x>, </x><given-names>X.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Xiong</surname><x>, </x><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><article-title>Modification of NaYF<sub>4</sub>:Yb, Er@SiO<sub>2</sub> Nanoparticles with Gold Nanocrystals for Tunable Green-to-Red Upconversion Emissions</article-title><source>J. Phys. Chem. C</source><x> </x><year>2011</year><x>, </x><volume>115</volume><x>, </x><fpage>3291</fpage><x>&ndash;</x><lpage>3296</lpage></citation></ref><ref id="ref25"><label>25. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit25"><name><surname>Eustis</surname><x>, </x><given-names>S.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>El-Sayed</surname><x>, </x><given-names>M. A.</given-names></name><article-title>Why Gold Nanoparticles Are More Precious Than Pretty Gold: Noble Metal Surface Plasmon Resonance and Its Enhancement of the Radiative and Nonradiative Properties of Nanocrystals of Different Shapes</article-title><source>Chem. Soc. Rev.</source><x> </x><year>2006</year><x>, </x><volume>35</volume><x>, </x><fpage>209</fpage><x>&ndash;</x><lpage>217</lpage></citation></ref><ref id="ref26"><label>26. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit26"><name><surname>Park</surname><x>, </x><given-names>H.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Choi</surname><x>, </x><given-names>W.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Hoffman</surname><x>, </x><given-names>R.</given-names></name><article-title>Effects of the Preparation Method of the Ternary CdS/TiO<sub>2</sub>/Pt Hybrid Photocatalysts on Visible Light-Induced Hydrogen Production</article-title><source>J. Mater. Chem.</source><x> </x><year>2008</year><x>, </x><volume>18</volume><x>, </x><fpage>2379</fpage><x>&ndash;</x><lpage>2385</lpage></citation></ref><ref id="ref27"><label>27. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit27"><name><surname>Buck</surname><x>, </x><given-names>M. R.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Schaak</surname><x>, </x><given-names>R. E.</given-names></name><article-title>Emerging Strategies for the Total Synthesis of Inorganic Nanostructures</article-title><source>Angew. Chem., Int. Ed.</source><x> </x><year>2013</year><x>, </x><volume>52</volume><x>, </x><fpage>2</fpage><x>&ndash;</x><lpage>27</lpage></citation></ref><ref id="ref28"><label>28. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit28"><name><surname>Wang</surname><x>, </x><given-names>C.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Yin</surname><x>, </x><given-names>H.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Dai</surname><x>, </x><given-names>S.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Sun</surname><x>, </x><given-names>S.</given-names></name><article-title>A General Approach to Noble Metal-Metal Oxide Dumbbell Nanoparticles and Their Catalytic Application for CO Oxidation</article-title><source>Chem. Mater.</source><x> </x><year>2010</year><x>, </x><volume>22</volume><x>, </x><fpage>3277</fpage><x>&ndash;</x><lpage>3282</lpage></citation></ref><ref id="ref29"><label>29. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit29"><name><surname>George</surname><x>, </x><given-names>C.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Dorfs</surname><x>, </x><given-names>D.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Bertoni</surname><x>, </x><given-names>G.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Falqui</surname><x>, </x><given-names>A.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Genovese</surname><x>, </x><given-names>A.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Pellegrino</surname><x>, </x><given-names>T.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Roig</surname><x>, </x><given-names>A.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Quarta</surname><x>, </x><given-names>A.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Comparelli</surname><x>, </x><given-names>R.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Curri</surname><x>, </x><given-names>M. L.</given-names></name><etal><italic>et</italic> <italic>al</italic>.</etal><article-title>A Cast-Mold Approach to Iron Oxide and Pt/Iron Oxide Nanocontainers and Nanoparticles with a Reactive Concave Surface</article-title><source>J. Am. Chem. Soc.</source><x> </x><year>2011</year><x>, </x><volume>133</volume><x>, </x><fpage>2205</fpage><x>&ndash;</x><lpage>2217</lpage></citation></ref><ref id="ref30"><label>30. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit30"><name><surname>Liu</surname><x>, </x><given-names>S.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Chen</surname><x>, </x><given-names>G.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Prasad</surname><x>, </x><given-names>P. N.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Swihart</surname><x>, </x><given-names>M. T.</given-names></name><article-title>Synthesis of Monodisperse Au, Ag, and Au-Ag Alloy Nanoaparticles with Tunable Size and Surface Plasmon Resonance Frequency</article-title><source>Chem. Mater.</source><x> </x><year>2011</year><x>, </x><volume>23</volume><x>, </x><fpage>4098</fpage><x>&ndash;</x><lpage>4101</lpage></citation></ref><ref id="ref31"><label>31. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit31"><name><surname>Huang</surname><x>, </x><given-names>J.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Sun</surname><x>, </x><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Huang</surname><x>, </x><given-names>S.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Yu</surname><x>, </x><given-names>K.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Zhao</surname><x>, </x><given-names>Q.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Peng</surname><x>, </x><given-names>F.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Yu</surname><x>, </x><given-names>Hao</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Wang</surname><x>, </x><given-names>H.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Yang</surname><x>, </x><given-names>J.</given-names></name><article-title>Crystal Engineering and SERS Properties of Ag-Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub> Nanohybrids: from Heterodimer to Core-Shell Nanostructures</article-title><source>J. Mater. Chem.</source><x> </x><year>2011</year><x>, </x><volume>21</volume><x>, </x><fpage>17930</fpage><x>&ndash;</x><lpage>17937</lpage></citation></ref><ref id="ref32"><label>32. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit32"><name><surname>Yang</surname><x>, </x><given-names>J.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Sargent</surname><x>, </x><given-names>E.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Kelley</surname><x>, </x><given-names>S.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Ying</surname><x>, </x><given-names>J. Y.</given-names></name><article-title>A General Phase-Transfer Protocol for Metal Ions and its Applications in Nanocrystal Synthesis</article-title><source>Nat. Mater.</source><x> </x><year>2009</year><x>, </x><volume>8</volume><x>, </x><fpage>683</fpage><x>&ndash;</x><lpage>689</lpage></citation></ref><ref id="ref33"><label>33. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit33"><name><surname>Peng</surname><x>, </x><given-names>S.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Wang</surname><x>, </x><given-names>C.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Xie</surname><x>, </x><given-names>J.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Sun</surname><x>, </x><given-names>S.</given-names></name><article-title>Synthesis and Stabilization of Monodisperse Fe Nanoparticles</article-title><source>J. Am. Chem. Soc.</source><x> </x><year>2006</year><x>, </x><volume>128</volume><x>, </x><fpage>10676</fpage><x>&ndash;</x><lpage>10677</lpage></citation></ref><ref id="ref34"><label>34. </label><citation citation-type="journal" id="cit34"><name><surname>Park</surname><x>, </x><given-names>J.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>An</surname><x>, </x><given-names>K.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Hwang</surname><x>, </x><given-names>Y.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Park</surname><x>, </x><given-names>J.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Noh</surname><x>, </x><given-names>H.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Kim</surname><x>, </x><given-names>J.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Park</surname><x>, </x><given-names>J.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Hwang</surname><x>, </x><given-names>N.</given-names></name><x>; </x><name><surname>Hyeon</surname><x>, </x><given-names>T.</given-names></name><article-title>Ultra-Large-Scale Synthesis of Monodisperse Nanocrystals</article-title><source>Nat. Mater.</source><x> </x><year>2004</year><x>, </x><volume>3</volume><x>, </x><fpage>891</fpage><x>&ndash;</x><lpage>895</lpage></citation></ref></ref-list></back></article>